For those who haven't read the plaque, we'll read the plaque.
那些尚未读过这块碑上内容的人们 我们为你朗读
“Here men from the planet Earth first set foot upon the moon."
“公元一九六九年七月
"July 1969."
地球人首次于此踏足月球
“We came in peace for all mankind."
我们谭代表全人类 为世界和平而来”
If this isn't an insanely beautiful woman, I'm hanging up.
如果不是漂亮美眉 我就马上挂断电话
Sir, I think you should listen to this.
先生，我、我想您应该听听这个
- Goddamn it! - Sir?
-嗅 ! 该死的 -先生?
Come on, baby. Come on!
快点 ， 宝贝。快点
This better not be another damn Russian spy job!
希望不会又是 俄国间恋飞机在捣乱
Air traffic say the skies are clear.
航空管理局的人说天上没东西
It's the real thing. A radio signal from another world.
这次是真的 来自另一个世界的无线电信和号
Let's not jump the gun here.
我、我们别高兴得太早
Get online with Space Command. They're gonna want to know...
接通太空控制中心 他们肯定想知道有关
What's with the golf balls? You're gonna kill me!
是谁放的高尔夫球 ? 差点摔死我了 !
Wait, this can't be right.
等等，等等。这是不可能的
The calculated distance from source is only 375,000km.
据计算，信和号源距此 仅有3 7了万5千公里
It's coming from the moon.
信和号来自月球
- Who else knows about this? - SETI in New Mexico identified a signal.
-谁还知道这件事 ? - 新墨西哥外星智慧中心发现这个信号
But, they're even more confused than we are, sir.
可是， 他们比我们还要困惑 长官…请原谅
- Major! - Yes, sir.
-少校? -是:长官!
Radar reception has been impaired, but we were able to get these.
雷达受到干扰 但是我们仍然接收到了一些影像
We estimate that it has a diameter of over 550km
我们估计 它的直径超过5 5 0 公里
and a mass roughly one fourth the size of our moon.
质量大约是月球的四分之一
What the hell is it? A meteor?
这到底是什么 ? 陨石 ?
- No, sir. - No, definitely not.
-不,长官 -不是， 肯定不是
- How do you know? - Well, sir, it's slowing down.
-你怎么知道 ? -哦，长官' 它正在减速
- It's what? - It's slowing down, sir.
-在什么 ? -它'呵' 它正在减速， 长官
Get me the Secretary of Defense.
给我接国防部长
Then wake him!
那就叫醒他 !
- Hello. - Hi.
-喂? -踢
- It's me.
-是我
- What time is it there? - It's 2:45 in the morning.
- 你那里现在几点 ? -潜晨两点四十五分
- [know I didn't wake you. - As a matter of fact, you did.
- 我想我没有吵醒你 -事实上你吵醒了我
Liar.
骗人
I have a confession to make.
我必须向你交代
I'm sleeping next to a beautiful, young brunette.
我的旁边睡着一位棕发美少女
You didn't let her stay up watching TV?
你没有让她整晚看电视肥 ?
- Did you? - Of course not. You're coming home
-有没有? - 当然没有
- right after the luncheon? - Yes, yes.
- 午宴一结束你就回家，是吗 ? -是的,是的' 是的
- Mommy? - Here's your mother.
-妈黑? -是你妈妈
- Hi, honey! - miss you.
-路 宝矶儿 - 路，我想你 - 我知道
President Whitmore's approval ratings have slipped below 40%...
怀特摩尔总统的支持率 已下滑到4 0 %以下
He's good.
他很好呀
Are the salad days over for President Whitmore?
怀特摩尔总统 是否仍显稚嫩 ，莫顿 ?
Leadership as a Gulf War pilot is different from leadership in politics...
在海湾战争中担任带队飞行员 与在政界担任领袖是截然不同的
Daddy let me watch Letterman.
答爸允许我看深夜电视节目
Traitor.
叛徒
They elected a warrior and got a wimp.
人民要选的是一名勇士 结果他却是惨夫
That game couldn't have been pretty.
这场比赛肯定不会好看
Thank you, sir.
谢谢，先生
Connie, you're up awfully early this morning.
康妮，你今天上午来得真时
They're not attacking your policies, they're attacking your age.
他们不是在攻击你的政策 而是你的年龄
“Whitmore seems less like the President and more like the orphaned child Oliver asking:
“怀特摩尔的表现不像总统 倒像是一个可怜的孤儿在
‘Please, sir, I'd like some more."
哀求 : “先生，求你再给点吧” ”
- That's clever. - I'm not laughing.
- 这个比喻很有趣 -是吗 ? 哦， 我笑不出来
Age was not an issue when you stuck to your guns. You were seen as young, idealistic...
只要你坚持己见，年龄就不是问题 人们曾认为你年轻， 富有理想
Now the message has gotten lost.
现在，人们已经不这样看了
It's too much politics, too much compromise.
太多的政治考量、太多的妥协让步
Isn't it amazing how quickly everyone can turn against you?
人们这么快就能反咬一口 真是有趣
Mr President, it's the Secretary of Defense.
对不起，总统先生 是国防部长的电话
Could you say that again?
你再说一遍好吗 ?
So why are you waiting?
哦，你还在等什么?咽 ?
My Social Security will expire, you'll still be sitting there.
我的救济金就要吃光了 可你还坐在那儿想
- I'm thinking. - Yeah, well, think already!
-我在思考 -是啊，想得够长了
Do you know how long it takes for those cups to decompose?
你知道那些杯子要 多长时间才会分解 ?
If you don't move soon, I'll start to decompose.
如果你不马上走 我就要开始分解了
Listen, David, I've been meaning to talk with you.
啊 ! 听着，戴维 我一直打算和你谈谈
- It's nice that you see me so much now... - Don't start, Dad.
- 我很高兴你能经常来看我，可是 -别，别提它，答爸
It's been... what? Four years? You're still wearing a wedding band?
我只想说已经过去。四年了吧 ? 可你仍然戴着结婚戒指
- Three years. - You're divorced, move on.
-三年 -好吧，管他几年。你已经离婚了
- This is not healthy. - No, the smoking is not healthy.
-好啦， 快走。这样做不健康 -不，这才不健康呢
Checkmate.
吸烟有害健康， 将军
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
等一下，等等，等等
- Wait. This is not checkmate. - See you tomorrow, Pop.
-等等，我还有…还没将死 - 明天见，答爸
Hold on! This is not checkmate.
等等你先别走，这肯定没有将死…
Oh... Checkmate!
将什么军啊将军 !
We've got everybody we have working on the problem.
我们这儿的所有人 都在处理这个问题
I love X-Files too. l hope you get to see it.
对， 我也喜欢看“义档案” 我希望你能看到它
David! What's the point in having a beeper if you don't turn it on?
戴维 ! 你有B P 机却不开机 那它还有什么用?
I was ignoring you.
我开机了“，只是不想理它
What's the big emergency?
到底有什么急事 ?
It started this morning. Every station's making like it's the 1950s.
从今天早晨开始 所有电视台都退回5 0年代了
We got static, snow, all kinds of distortions. Nobody knows...
又是干扰、又是雪花 画面有多种失真，谁都不知道
There's a reason we have bins labelled "Recycle".
不知道这儿为什么贴着 “回收”的标签吗 ?
What the hell is going on? My God in heaven!
你们到底想于什么 ? 我的天哪
So sue me. David! We got a problem!
别指着我 ! 戴维，我们有麻烦了
Did you switch transponder channels?
你们， 呵 试过切换到转发频道吗 ?
Please! You think I'd be this panicked if it was so simple?
噢， 拜托。如果就那么简单 我还会这么紧张吗 ?
OK, let's point the dish at another satellite.
好吧， 可以把天线对准其它卫星
We tried that. It didn't work. It's almost as though they weren't there.
我们试过了“，还是没用 好像所有卫星都已经不存在了一样
All right. What have we got here?
好吧，我们这儿测到什么了 ?
This is impossible.
这不可能
- The signal's all screwed up. - Stop it! Just leave it alone. You'll break it!
-哦，信号一塌糊涂 - 别再敲了，它迟早得坏在你的手上
It's so fuzzy.
为什么这么模糊 ?
Oh, no.
贡 ' 不好
Morning, Lucas.
晤上好 ' 卢卡斯
You see these? 1 got a whole goddamn crop full of these.
看见了吗 ? 我的地里全是这些玩意儿
If your father's not in the air in 20 minutes, I'm getting someone else.
要是你和爸爸 2 0 分钟之内还不起飞 我就另请高明
- Russell! - Hey, Miguel!
-嘿 ! 卢塞尔 ! -嘿!米盖尔 !
Russell! What are you doing?
卢塞尔 ! 你在于什么? !
Just what in the hell do you think you're doing?
你知道自己都于了些什么吗 ?
It's the wrong field, you idiot!
你撒错地方了，白疾 !
Lucas's farm's on the other side of town!
卢卡斯的农场在镇子的另一边
Are you sure?
你肯定吗 ?
CNS is running a story that we're covering up a nuclear-testing experiment.
CN S正在报导 称我们对外隐瞒了某类核试验
They can run with it if they want to embarrass themselves.
好啊，告诉他们 如果不怕出丑就尽管传吧
NASA wants to know our position.
太空总署追了我一个上午 他们想知道我们的立场
Our official position is we have no official position.
我们的“官方”立场就是 …我们没有官方立场
- What is going on here? - Guys, would I keep you out of the loop?
-康妮,到底发生了什么事 ? -诸位难道我还能眶着你们吗 ?
- Absolutely. - What? I can't hear you.
-是的 - 有什么新鲜事 ? 我听不见
At the moment our satellites are somewhat unreliable.
目前， 我们的卫星都不怎么可靠
Isn't it possible that this thing may just pass us by?
这个东西是否有可能 仅仅掠过地球呢 ?
What if it doesn't. Why don't we target some ICBMs to blow it up?
万一不是掠过怎么办 ? 为何不发射儿枚弹道导弹将它摧毁 ?
And risk turning one dangerous falling object into many?
这样将有许多碎片飞向地球
We don't yet know enough to make any kind of intelligent judgments.
我们还不清楚要对付的是什么 无法作出明智的判断
Luckily the press is making up their own story for now.
幸运的是 新闻界正对这一事件胡乱猜测
But that's not gonna keep.
不过这种状况不会长久
- We may need to upgrade to DEFCON 3. - Absolutely.
-我们也许应进入三级防空戒备状态 -绝对需要
General, tell NORAD we're on DEFCON 3.
将军，和防空司令部联系 告诉他们进入三级戒备状态
- That's not what the President said. - Isn't that a bit premature?
-总统不是这么说的 - 你不觉得这么做操之过急吗 ?
Over 50% of the armed forces are on weekend leave.
百分之五十以上的三军部队 都在休周未假期
Plus the commanders and troops that are in town for the Fourth of July parade.
更不用说那些正准备参加 独立日检阅的部队
The object has settled into a stationary orbit.
情报部门说那个物体 已进入固定轨道
- Well, that's good news. - Not really, sir.
-哦，是个好消息 -啊， 未必' 长官
Part of it has broken off into nearly three dozen pieces.
它的一部分已经 分裂成3 0 多个碎片
Smaller than the whole, yet over 15 miles in width themselves.
比母体小， 可是 其本身直径也超过1 5 英里
- This had better be good. - Admiral on deck!
- 这个最好是真的 -舰长到 !
Sir, we're looking at a total radar blackout over a 13km area.
长官， 我们的雷达现在 在1 3公里范围内收不到任何信号
- Let's do a diagnostic check. - Excuse me, sir.
- 进行修复性检查 -对不起， 长官 ?
The radar may be malfunctioning, but the infrared is totally off the map.
雷达可能出现故障 红外信号也在图上完全消失
Jeez!
天哪
Get me Atlantic Command.
马上给我接大西洋司令部
Hang on, sir.
等一下， 长官
We have visual range with incoming over Iraqi air space.
长官: 我们在伊拉克上空 目击到飞行物
- Second sighting? - Yes, sir. Just came in from the Persian Gulf.
-第二次吗 ? -对 ' 长官' 这是刚从波斯湾发来的
Correction, sir.
更正，长官
We have two confirmed visual contacts.
现在已有两次经核实的目击
Mr President, they're tracking another one off the California coastline!
肯定无误。总统先生 另一个已经到达加州海岸
All right, put it on. General, you might wanna watch this.
好的， 去吧，把电视打开 将军，你也许想看看这个
Ladies and gentlemen, we are interrupting our regular broadcast
女士们先生们 我们用临时播播的方式
to bring you extraordinary events taking place in Russia.
向您报道发生在俄国的不寻常事件
This unexplained disturbance and the resulting hysteria are incredible.
这种无法解释的现象和由此 产生的恐慌令人难以置信
How would you describe what you are seeing?
请描述一下你看到的东西 ?
it is clearing the mountains, moving too slowly to be a comet or meteor.
它越过山脉，移动缓慢 不可能是彗星或者陨石
Widespread panic has gripped the countryside as
丽惧笼置着大地
thousands have taken to the streets.
数千人涌上街头
it is confirmed. The unexplained phenomenon is headed for Moscow.
不明物体飞越大地' 已经核实 不明物体现正飞向莫斯科
We have an AWAC off the West Coast.
我们在西海岸布有预警机
ETA with contact point, three minutes.
估计三分钟后就能与之接触
Don't understand it, sir. Side radar doesn't see a thing.
真搞不明白， 长官 侧疝雷达什么也没发现
I know! I'm blind, sir. Nothing is registering.
是的，雷达瞎了 长官。什么也没发现
Negative. We have zero visibility. Visibility is at zero.
没有迹象，能见度为堆
Command, this is Eagle Eye 370.
司令部 启眼 3 7 0 报告
Captain, the President is listening. Repeat what you just told me.
机长， 总统正在听 重复你刚才的报告
We still have zero visibility.
能见度仍然为堆
Instrumentation is malfunctioning.
仪器出现故障
We can't get any kind of reading on what's in front of us.
我们无法看到前方的情况
Wait a minute.
等等
it may be clearing.
也许能看见了
Pull out!
有疏升 !
- Line's gone, sir. - Two more spotted over the Atlantic.
-线断了长官 - 大西洋上空又发现两个
One's moving toward New York, the other here.
一个正飞向纽约 一个则朝这里来了
- How long do we have? - Less than 10 minutes.
- 我们还有多少时间 ? -不到十分钟
Mr President, I recommend we move you to a secure location.
总统先生，我强烈建议 立刻把你送到安全地点
- Connie, can we expect the same panic? - More than likely.
- 这里会否出现和俄国同样的恐慌 ? - 非常可能
- We can discuss this on the way. - I'm not leaving.
-总统先生， 我们可以在路上讨论 -我不会走
We have to maintain a working government.
我们必须保证政府的正常运行
Take the Vice President, the whole cabinet, and the Joint Chiefs to a secured location.
你们带副总统全体内效和参谋长 联席会员到一个安全地点
I'm staying.
我留下来
1 don't want to add to a public hysteria that's gonna cost lives.
我不想引起公众的 骚乱从而造成人员伤亡
Connie, we'll initiate the emergency broadcast system.
康妮 ' 我们启动紧急广播系统
We'll advise people not to panic.
劝告人民不要惊慌
The best idea right now is to stay in their homes.
目前最好的办法就是呆在家里
Yes, sir. Roy? Dean?
是， 先生。罗伊 ? 狄恩?
Have the cabinet members rendezvous here. We'll take them to NORAD.
让所有内效成员在这儿集合 我们带他们去北美防空司令部
Mr President, with your permission, I'd like to remain at your side.
总统先生，如果您允许 我请求和你在一起
I had a feeling you would.
我知道你会这样的
What happens if they do become hostile?
如果他们真的有敌意怎么办 ?
Then God help us.
那只能求上帝保佑我们了
There it is. The strange atmospheric phenomenon.
请大家注意这种奇怪的大气现象
it is apparently what is causing all the distortions...
显然正是它导致电视图像的变形
David, are you watching this?
戴维，你在看这个吗 ?
There is no evidence that these phenomena are endangering anyone.
对此事的反应不应造成恐慌 还没有证据表明这种现象具有威胁
Thus far, reports of oppression...
到目前为止， 有关报告
Marty, I got a lock on that signal pattern so we can filter it out.
马迪，我对这个信号的规律 进行了研究，因此可以把它过滤出来
But if my calculations are right, it'll be gone in seven hours.
如果，如果我的计算没错的话 它将在大约七个小时之后消失
It's reducing itself every time it recycles so eventually it'll disappear.
它每过一个周期都有所减弱 因此最终它将消失…
- Are you listening? - Can you believe this?
- 你在听吗 ? -简直难以置信 ! 戴维
Haven't you been watching? David!
你还没看电视吗 ? 戴维 ?
Good afternoon. So far the phenomenon has not caused any damage.
谢谢你将军， 下午好 目前，不明物体还没有造成破坏
We have to ask you to stay calm, and it's important for everyone not to panic.
我们晨请公众努力保持镇静 重要的是大家都不要惊慌
We have a fix on three of the occurrences about to appear...
我们已经证实不明物体将出现在 三个美国城市上空
- It's just unreal. - Miguel, come here!
- 真是难以置信 -嘿 , 米盖尔， 快来
One is headed towards Los Angeles.
一个向洛杉矶飞去
The other two are headed towards New York and Washington, DC.
另外两个飞向东部海岸 分别前往纽约和华盛顿特区
Marty.
马迪 ? 马迪?
Jamie says this building has an old bomb shelter.
杰米说这座楼有个旧防空洞
- We're heading down there now. - Everybody! Head down to the basement.
-我们正准备下去 -好吧。阿' 大家都去地下室
Take it slow, don't run. Walk down to the basement!
别着急，别跑。都到地下室去
There's no shame in hiding.
租起来并不丢人
I'd better call my mother.
噢,我最好给我妈打个电话
Russ, I heard you had a little trouble this morning. Dusted the wrong field.
罗斯，我听说你今天晤上有点麻烦 把药撒错地方了?
I know you're probably still a little confused from your hostage experience.
我想，那次被劫持可能 让你到现在还胡里胡涂的
Hostage experience? Did something happen to you, Russ?
你被劫持 ” 有些什么遭遇 ， 罗斯 ?
Years back he was kidnapped by aliens. Did all kind of experiments on him and such.
好象是数年前，这位仁兄被 外星人绑架 ' 在其身上进行各种试验
Tell ‘em about it, Russ. Get a few beers in him and he'll tell you all about it.
跟他们说说，罗斯 灌他两杯啤酒，他就把一切都告诉你
Won't you, Russ?
奇谈怪论。说说吧，罗斯 ?
Russ, when they took you up in their spaceship, did they do any...
罗斯， 他们把你拖上飞船以后 对你做过什么…
sexual things? Do you recall? Do you recollect?
性侵犯之类的事情 ? 你还记得吗 ?
- What's that? - Let's get outta here.
-那是什么 ? -我们快点离开这儿 ! 马上 !
Wow!
哦!
Mommy, lookit!
妈咪' 快看 !
It's too early, baby.
天还没亮呢，宝页
- Is it an earthquake? - Not even a four-pointer.
- 好像是地震了 ? “-连四级都不到
Go back to sleep.
接着睡吧
Daddy!
驳地 !
What are you doing here?
你在这儿于什么 ?
- You should be in the shelter. - What's going on?
- 你应当到防空洞去 - 发生什么事了 ?
- Aren't you coming, David? - I gotta see this.
- 你不下去吗 ? 戴维 ? - 我得去看看
The signal!
信和号
My God!
噢， 我的天哪 !
Now what do we do?
现在怎么办?
Address the nation.
向全国广播
There's gonna be a lot of frightened people out there.
将会出现大批惊恐万状的民众
Yeah.
是吗 ?
I'm one of ‘em.
我是其中之一
Hey! Come on!
嘿'嘿'嘿'下去
He's just trying to impress you.
它只是想讨好你
If you wanna impress me, you need to get a job and stop slobberin' all over my shoes.
如果它想讨好我，就去找份工作 而且别再徐我的鞋
I don't believe this. Jasmine!
真是不敢相信
Neighbours are movin’ out. 1 guess they finally got tired of all these quakes.
邻居们都在搬家，我想他们是给 这地震搞烦了
A little shake and they runnin’.
小小的地震就把他们吓傻了
Police and fire departments want everyone to stay off the phone.
警方和消防部门 晨请所有人不要打电话
There's something on the news about the quake!
电视里正在播地震的消息
What's up, man? What you doin’ goin’ out there?
-怎么了,小子 ? - 你在外面于什么呢 ?
Shooting aliens.
射那些外星人
Oh, you shootin’ aliens. You think you're tough, huh? What you got? Turn around.
在开枪打外星人吗 ? 你认为你 很强壮，咽 ? 你拿着什么 ? 转过去
Come on, let's get you something to eat.
好咬,我给你做点东西吃吧
- Watch out! Watch it now! - I'm gonna go grab the paper.
-哦，好了。别半了。别闹了 -我出去拿报纸
Dylan!
迪伦 !
Come on, honey. Let's go!
快点， 宝贝 快点走吧
Babe, you want some of this coffee?
宝贝， 你想喝点咖啡吗 ?
Babe?
宝页?
over the capitals of india, England and Germany,
已有更多的飞船到达印度 英国和德国首都上空
bringing estimates up to between 10 and 15 of these city-size spacecraft.
伦敦、莫斯科、书黎' 估计有到1 5 稻飞船，其大小与这些城市差不多
I know, Ma. Just try and stay calm.
我明白，妈。你要保持镇静
- Tell her to leave town. - Why? What happened?
-告诉她收拾行李离开城市 -为什么?怎么了 ?
- Just do it! - Ma, listen!
- 照我说的做 ! -噢'妈?妈'了听着1
Get your stuff together and head for Aunt Esther's.
把东西收拾一下 到艾丝特姨妈那去
Don't argue with me! Just go!
别和我和争了 ! 快走!
David! Why did I just send my mother to Atlanta?
戴维，我为什么要把我妈 送到亚特兰大 ?
David, talk to me.
戴维 ? 告诉我吧
The signal in the satellite feed is recycling down to extinction. Didn't you hear me?
我不是告诉你们隐藏在卫星馈波中 的信号正在缓慢地减弱 ?
- Not really. - Countdown.
-我没听见 - 倒计时
A countdown? To what, David?
倒计时。是什么倒计时 ?戴维?
It's like in chess. First you strategically position your pieces.
哦，就和下棋一样 首先把你的棋子布好位置
Then, when the timing's right, you strike. See?
然后等到时机成熟就…出击
They're positioning themselves everywhere using one signal to synchronise their efforts.
看，外星人正在全球布下棋子 用这个信号使他们的行动同步
In about six hours, the signal's gonna disappear and the countdown will be over.
大约六小时后，信号就会消失 倒计时也将结束
And then what?
那然后呢 ?
Checkmate.
将军
Oh, my God!
噢 ' 我的天 ! 噢， 我的天 !
Oh, my God, I gotta call my brother.
噢 ， 我的天 ! 我得告诉我兄弟
I'd better call my housekeeper, and my lawyer!
我还得告诉保姆 我得告诉我的律师 !
Ah, forget my lawyer.
哦，律师就免了
Ladies and gentlemen, the President of the United States.
女士们先生们 美国总统发表讲话
Good afternoon.
下午好
My fellow Americans,
美国同胞们
a historic and unprecedented event has occurred.
史无前例的历史性事件发生了
The question of whether or not we're alone in the universe
我们人类是否是宇宙中唯一智慧 生物的问题…
has been answered.
已经有了答案
Although it's understandable that many of us feel hesitation or fear,
我们中的很多人有敌对感 甚至恐惧感是可以理解的
we must attempt to reserve judgment.
但现在还不能作出判断
He says he's your husband.
他说是你丈夫
Oh, God.
噢，上帝
- What do you want? - You gotta leave the White House.
-你有什么事 ? -哦，你必须马上离开白宫
This is hardly the time to be having that old discussion.
现在的时间和地点 不适合讨论这些老问题
You gotta leave Washington.
你不明白。你必须离开华盛顿
In case you haven't noticed, we are having a little crisis here!
难道你不知道吗 我们正在经历一场小小的危机
They have a hidden signal. They're gonna attack.
外星人用隐藏的信号联系 他们就要进攻了
- You are just being paranoid! - It's not paranoia!
-你有点太多疑了 - 这不是多疑
The embedding's very subtle. It was probably overlooked...
他们隐藏得很巧妙 很容易被忽略掉
Marty, get out of town as soon as you can. Please?
马迪， 你在这儿于吗 ? 尽快离开这座城市。拜托
The staff and I will remain here as we attempt to communicate.
我和我的幕僚将留在白宫 设法与他们进行沟通
if you feel compelled to leave these cities, please do so in an orderly fashion.
如果你们急于离开城市 也务必要维持好秩序
Excuse me! Coming through.
对不起， 让一让
The arrival of the aliens has caused over 10,000 fender benders in just a few seconds.
外星客人的到来在瞬间之内 就已造成一万多次小型交通事故
But this is just the beginning...
不过这仅仅是开始
- You can't go! You got to call them back! - I'm not gonna do this with you, Jasmine.
- 你不能走' 你必须给他们回电话 ! - 我不会这样做的，贾丝敏
- I've got to report to El Toro. - You said you was on leave for the Fourth!
-我必须回基地报到 -可你说过你正在休独立日长假
Well, they cancelled it!
是啊，可是被取消了 !
Look, why are you acting like this?
喂，你怎么变成这个样 ?
Why?
为什么 ?
That's why!
这就是原因 !
Look, I really don't think they flew 90 billion light years to come and start a fight,
哎，我也不相信他们飞了 9 0 0 亿光年到这就是为了开战
and get all rowdy.
于得天下大乱
Why don't you just relax? I'm gonna report to El Toro, find out what's goin’ on.
你尽管放心好了“， 我到基地去报到 看看究竟怎么回事
- What are you doin’ in there, man? - Nothing, I'm just drivin’.
- 你在车里于什么 ? -没事，我在开车
Look.
看
- I got these for you. - Firecrackers!
-嘿' 这是给你的 -革炮 ?
- You be careful. - Steve, wait.
-哦，你要小心点 -等等，史莹文
- wanna tell you something. - What is it, Jasmine?
-我有话要说 -说什么' 贾丝敏 ?
You take care of yourself, you hear?
你自己多保重， 好吗 ?
why don't you pack some things and you and Dylan come stay with me on the base?
你可以收拾好行李 带着迪伦和我一起回基地去
You will see that there is nothing to be scared of.
这样你就会知道没什么可怕的
Really?
真的?
- You don't mind? - Well, I mean...
- 你不介意 ? -喝 ， 我想
I will have to let all my other girlfriends know they can't come over.
我可以告诉我的 其他那些女朋友先不要来
- I got to postpone a freaky weekend. - There you go, thinking you're all that.
- 我得推掉几个美妙的周末约会 -你又来了' 你又来了
But you are not as charming as you think you are, sir.
自以为是个情圣 别以为自己长得有多潇洒 ， 长官
Yes, lam.
我就是帅
- Them big old Dumbo ears. - Look at you with them chicken legs.
-看你的煽风耳 -哦，看你的小鸡腿
Come on, Dylan.
过来，迪伦
Look out!
嘿!喔!
The television said they started looting. Vultures.
电视上说有人开始抢劫了 贪得无厌
- Do you still have the Plymouth? - David, you don't have a licence.
- 你想借我的车 ? -戴维， 你没有驾照哇
- You're driving. - Yeah, I'm... I'm driving?
- 你来开 -好 ， 我开…我来开?
Come on.
没错。快点
I really want you out of Los Angeles.
我希望你马上离开洛杉矶
You're staying there to keep people calm. I won't let them criticise you for it.
你留在那儿稳定人心是很正确的 我不会让你在这方面受到反击
- l appreciate your trying to help me. - Liar. Stick to the truth. You're good at it.
-谢谢你努力帮助我 - 骗人。要坚持真理正是你的长处
OK. I don't want you in any one of those cities.
好吧。我希望你 不要留在任何城市中
I'll leave as soon as the interviews are done.
会见一结束我马上就走
All right. A helicopter will be taking you to Nellis.
好的，有架直升机在等你 他们会把你带到内利斯〈空军基地 )
- And the munchkin? - She'll meet you there.
-孩子怎么办 ? -她也会去那儿跟你会合
All right. I love you.
好吧。我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
- Bye.
-再见
It 's the White House!
那儿可是白宫' 不能大喊大叫
- You can't drive up and ring a bell. - Can't you go any faster?
- 你以为按按门铃就能进去 ? - 你还能再快点吗 ?
You think they don't know what you know? She works for the President.
你以为你知道的他们会不知道 ? 他们知道，相信我。好为总统工作
- They know everything. - They don't know this.
-他们什么都知道 -他们不知道这个
You're gonna educate them, huh? So are you so smart?
噢，噢，你要给他们上课吗 ? 好啊，我来问你， 你有那么精明吗 ?
How come you spent eight years in MIT to become a cable repairman?
你在麻省理工学院学了八年 却当了光缆修理工
All I'm saying is they got people who handle these things.
我的意思是他们会派人去处理的
If they want HBO, they'll call you. Look at these people, look.
他们想看电视才会找你 看看、看看这些人。看呀
Vultures. They take and then they go.
贪得无厌。他们拿了东西就跑
They're going faster than we are. We're in the fast lane!
他们在跑，而且比我们跑得快 看看 我们在快车道上
- They're cutting me off. - No one's cutting you off!
- 有人挡在前面 -没人挡在前面。我们要吃罚单了
- They're getting in front. I can't go faster. - [don't wanna argue.
-他们正在超车 我不能再快了 - 我不和你争 !
- Let's just get there, quickly. - What's the rush?
-我们尽快赶到吧 -着什么急 ' 咽 ?
You think we'll get to Washington and it won't be there?
你以为我们去晚了 华盛顿就没了吗 ?
A crop-duster was arrested as he dropped leaflets from the air.
当地一位农药播撒员今天 因从空中向市政厅抛撤传单而被逮捕
- Everybody's leavin’. - Can you give us some of your time?
- 大家都走了 -能耽性你一些时间吗 ?
We've got to stop them! I was kidnapped by space aliens ten years ago!
我们必须阻止他们 ! 十年前我被外星人绑架了 !
They did all kinds of experiments on me!
他们在我身上做各种试验 !
They've been studying us, finding out our weaknesses!
他们研究我们很多年了 寻找我们的弱点 !
We've gotta stop ‘em. They're gonna kill us all!
我们必须阻止他们 他们会把我们全杀光 !
Some people attribute his behaviour to post-traumatic stress
一些人把他的异常行为 归咎于在越南服役时
from his service as a pilot in Vietnam.
遭遇创伤后的紧张综合症
Others have a more unusual theory.
不过， 其他人还有更新奇的观点
How would you describe Mr Casse?
你们怎么看凯西先生 ?
- Keeps to himself. Quiet. - Private.
-不与人交往 -内向
When they took him up in the spaceship,
外星人把他拖上飞船时
the aliens abused him sexually.
对他进行虐待，那方面的
Mr Casse is in the county lockup...
山西先生今晚被关在县看守所
Pack up. We're leaving.
收拾一下，我们走
He may be released fater tonight...
准备从轻发落，今天晚些时候 他有可能被释放
Miguel, what about Dad?
米盖尔，答答怎么办 ?
This could be our last night on Earth.
这也许是我们在地球的最后一夜
You don't wanna die a virgin, do you?
你不想死时还是处女肥 ?
- Come on! We're going. - No, I'm not goin' anywhere.
-快点' 我们走 ! -不:我哪也不去 !
Thanks a lot, partner! Remember. Get as far away from these things as you can!
多谢了，哥儿们。记住 离开这些城市，越远越好
You read my mind!
你们真了解我 !
We gotta get as far away from these things as we can!
我们要离开这一切，越远越好 !
- They let you out? - You damn right!
-他们放你出来了 ? -你说对了 !
They got bigger fish to fry now, believe you me!
他们有更大的事要做， 相信我吧
Come on, boy!
走吧， 孩子 !
Do you think we can find something better to do with our time?
我们只能靠着看电视 打发时间吗， 先生们 ?
Where you been, Stevie?
你去哪了，史蔓文 ?
Man, this is unbelievable. This is, like, huge.
令人难以置信。事情好像很大
- They've recalled everybody. - Looks like the mail's still working.
-他们召回了所有的人 -哦，看来邮局还在工作
You'll have to do the honours for me.
还是请你帮忙念一下吧
- You're a wuss! - Whatever. Shut up and read it.
- 你这个胆小鬼 -对，就算是。闭嘴。快念
It says: "Captain Steven Hiller"... loser.
信上说“史芝文， 希勒上尉” 失败者
- Come on! - Blah blah blah!
-快念，快念，快念 ! - 鸣阶哆咬唉哟唉啦
“We regret to inform you that despite your excellent record of service..."
“我们遗憾地通知你 尽管您的记录非常优秀”
I'm sorry, man. You know what you need to do?
很遗憾，朋友 你知道你该怎么办吗 ?
You need to, like, kiss some serious booty to get ahead in this world.
要想在世上出人头地 就得学着拍马屁 !
That's what I'm trying to tell you. See, I like the one-knee approach,
这就是我要告诉你的
because it puts the booty, like, right in front of the lip...
因为这样屁股就在 你的面前…
- What's this? - That's nothin’.
-这是什么 ? -哦，没什么
What is this?
等一下 ! 等一下。这是什么 ?
- Jasmine kinda has a thing for dolphins. - Stevie, this is a wedding ring.
- 贾丝敏就喜欢海豚。我不明白 -史芝文， 这是结婚戒指
I thought you said you were gonna break it off?
我记得你说过要和她分手 ?
Well...
是的，我
Man, you know I really like Jasmine.
我想说，你知道我真的喜欢贾丝敏
You know that, right?
你知道的，是吗 ?
Man, you're never gonna get to fly the space shuttle if you marry a stripper.
伙计，如果你必了脱衣舞文 就永远和坪想开航天飞机
it could only happen in California. Here's Wendy Walsh with a special report.
只有在加州才会发生这种事 这里是文迪' 沃斯的特别报告
Hundreds of UFO fanatics have gathered on rooftops in Los Angeles
有数百名U F 0爱好者聚集在 洛杉矶市中心这座大厦的楼顶
to welcome the new arrivals.
欢迎外星来客
Oh, God! I hope they bring back Elvis!
贡 ' 天哪 我希望他们能让猫王复活 !
I just came in to get my check tonight and I got talked into working.
我今晚是来拿支票的 可还是上了台
Oh, I must have been trippin’.
哦，我真是昏了头了
It's the party event of the century!
这个活动被称作世纪大聚会
Everyone is invited, especially you-know-who.
人人都可以参加 尤其是这个节目的观众
- This is so cool! - Girl, please!
- 真是太酷了 ! -得了' 小姐
Oh, hey! I made it before I came in.
哦，嘿 ! 这是我来之前做的
Check it out!
你看看
I know you're not gonna join those idiots.
哦，你不会是要参加 那个思春的聚会吧 ?
l am going over there as soon as I get off.
哦，我一下班就到那儿去
- Do you wanna come? - Tiffany, listen to me a sec.
- 你想来吗 ? - 狄劳妮，听我说一名
Now promise me you won't.
答应我你不去
Come on, girl! Promise me.
好啦， 小姐，答应我
I promise.
我保证
OK.
好的
Look, I'm out of town for a while. Later.
我到城外去一会儿。再见
Everyone is trying to get out of Washington. We're the only schmucks trying to get in.
全世界的人都在设法逃离华盛顿 我们是唯一往里钻的傻瓜
What the hell is that?
这是什么东西 ?
Pops, this is every phone book in America.
和葡，这是全美国的电话薄
You think an important person like Constance will be listed?
你认为像康妮这样的 重要人物也会被列出来 ?
Demonstrators in front of the White House are protesting
白宫前的示威者 抗议政府对与外星人的
the military involvement with our first contact with the alien visitors.
首次接触进行军事干涉
So?
那么…
Do you wanna ring the bell, or should I?
是你去按门铃还是我来 ?
- Perfect, she's using it. - What? It's busy?
-哦，好极了。她在用 -什么?什么?什么?占线?
Yeah, I can use her signal to triangulate her exact position in the White House.
对 。我可以利用她的信和号 测定她在白宫的准确位置
- You can do that? - Yeah.
- 你能办到吗 ? -能
All cable repairmen can, Pops.
所有光继修理工都会这个
The visitors have arrived, but the President remains at the White House.
外星人来了 可总统还留在白宫里
Question. Are Mr Whitmore's actions a) ultra brave or b) foolhardy?
问题是 : 总统的行动是 A， 勇猛无比， 还是B“，有勇无谋
- What? - Don't hang up, sweetie.
-什么? -哦，别挂断， 亲爱的
David! How did you get this number?
戴维 ? ! 你怎么知道这个号码 ?
- Do me a favour. Walk to the window. - And I'm looking for what?
-啊，劳您大驾，到窗边来 -让我看什么 ?
You'll see.
你会看见的
Over here.
在这儿
See us?
看见了吗 ?
How does he do that?
他可真有本事
In light of our apparent inability to communicate with the visitors
我们现在是从由于我们显然 无法与外星来客进行沟通
Pentagon officials have retrofit this Skylift helicopter
国防部特别在这架直升机上
with a visual communications device.
加装了光学通讯装置
- Mr President. - Gentlemen, be seated.
一 总统先生 -请坐' 先生们
- Where are we now? - We're commencing liftoff.
-现在怎么样了 ? -他们正在起飞
wand refitted with these enormous light panels
而且，在机身上加装了
that are attached to the hull and onto the sides.
多个巨大的灯板，分布在两侧
Echo One, Welcome Wagon is in the air.
一号 ，“迎宾马车”已经升空
I repeat, Welcome Wagon is in the air.
重复 ，“迎宾马车”已经升空
Roger, Welcome Wagon. Echo One, right beside you.
收到，“迎宾马车” 我是“回声一号”“， 我们就在你旁边
This is something I would never believe that I would be! In the White House!
我这辈子也不敢相信 我居然能进白宫 ! 瞧瞧这儿 !
If knew I was gonna meet the President, 1 would have worn a tie.
嘿，时知道能见总统 我就打条领带
Look at me, I look like a schlemiel.
我是说，你看我看上去像个乞丐
- Oy, my God! - David,
-啊，我的天 - 戴维
- [ don't know if he'll want to see you. - Then we're wasting time, we should go.
-我不知道他是否高兴见你 - 我们在浪费时间，我们就走
- Why wouldn't he listen? - Last time I saw him, we had a fight.
-为什么 ? 他为什么不听 ? - 因为我上次见到他时我们打了一架
You walked in and punched him in the head.
你走进房间，猛击他的脑袋
- The President! - He wasn't president then.
-你打了总统 ? -不' 他当时还不是总统
I punched him, he fought back. It was a fight!
我打他，他也打我 我们扭成一团， 一场好打
A fight that you started! David thought I was having an affair.
是你挑起来的 戴维以为我有了外遇
- With the President? - Which I wasn't!
- 和总统 ? -我当然没有 !
Either go get him, or we should head back.
听着，要么你去找他 要么我们回车上去
All right, I'll get him. Wait here, and don't touch anything!
好吧，我，我去找他 你们在这等。什么东西也别碰
You punched the President?
你居然把总统给打了 ?
God!
天哪 !
Nearing point of contact, Echo One. We're closing in.
接近联络点了，“回声一号” 我们正在接近
Roger that. Begin sequence when ready.
收到。准备好后就按计划行事
The three choppers are approaching
三架直升机正在逐步接近
what has been unanimously agreed to be the front of these spaceships...
那里被认定是外星飞船的正面
You're leaving now?
你现在走吗 ?
Hey, see if they've got those pens they give away.
戴维， 你看那些笔 是不是用来送人的 ?
Dad, what?
你说什么 ?
I don't have a choice...
我没有别的选择
- [don't have time for this. - Two minutes, Tom, please.
- 我没时间理会这个 - 两分钟
Mr President, Julius Levinson. David is my...
总统先生，朱利叶斯利文森 戴维是我儿子
- [told you he wouldn't listen. - You have to tell him now.
- 我说过，他不会听的 -不'你现在必须告诉他
David, you have to tell him! David, tell him!
告诉他。戴维，你必须告诉他
I know why we have satellite disruption.
我知道卫星信号为什么中断
All right. Go ahead.
好的，说吧
Let's say that you wanted to coordinate with spaceships on different sides of the Earth.
好的。比如说你想与分布在 地球各处的宇宙飞船联络
They couldn't send a direct signal, right?
你不可能靠一个直线信号，对吗 ?
- You mean line of sight? - Right. The curve of the Earth prevents it.
- 你是说“波的直线传播” -对 ' 正是地球的曲线阻碍传播
You'd need satellites to relay that signal in order to reach each ship.
为了联络各飞船 你需要用卫星中继信号
Well, l found a signal hidden inside our own satellite system.
我发现在我们的 卫星信号中隐藏着另一信号
Excuse me, Mr President. They're starting.
对不起，总统先生。他们开始了
They're using our own satellites against us.
他们利用我们的卫星来对付我们
The clock is ticking.
时间已经不多了
- Bringing it in to hover. - Welcome Wagon,
- 转入悬停状态 - “迎宾马车”
Echo One. Approaching alien ship.
我是“回声一号”。接近外星飞船
Initiating communication sequence.
启动沟通计划 ，“回声一号”
Welcome Wagon has commenced.
“迎宾马车”已经启动
General Grey, coordinate with the Atlantic Command. Tell them to evacuate the cities.
格雷将军和大西洋司令部联络 告诉他们尽可能地
Get those helicopters away from the ship. Call them back!
朴散各城市中的居民，岂直升机 离开飞船 ， 让他们立即撤回
- What the hell's going on? - We're leaving. Kim! My daughter.
- 究竟怎么回事 ? -我们撤离。吉姆 ? 我的女儿呢 ?
Something's happening.
啊，这里有些情况
They're responding.
他们有所反应 !
Something is happening.
有个东西打开了
It looks like there's activity. This may be a response, Echo One.
看来他们将采取某种行动 可能是某种应答，“回声一号”
We see it too. Can't identify it.
我们也看见了“，无法确定
Load the rest of the staff in the second helicopter.
其余的幕僚 上第二架直升机 !
- Is my wife in the air? - She will be shortly.
-我夫人上飞机了吗 ? -很快就可以了
Nice. Very nice.
好 ' 很好
Good! Close the door! Hatch secure!
好了“，关上门。注意安全
We have our own phone.
看，我们有专用电话
Move outta here.
我们现在该走了
The President's ordered an evacuation.
总统已经下令撤退
Our prayers go out to the pilots‘ families.
为那些勇敢的飞行员的 妻儿们祈祷吧
- Indeed, God help us all. - Mrs Whitmore.
- 愿上帝保佑所有人 -总统夫人 ?
Authorities have called for the evacuation of Los Angeles County.
当局建议洛杉矶市民 全部撤离城市
People are advised to avoid the highways wherever possible.
并建议人们尽可能不要上高速路
Great! Now he tells me.
好啊。你现在才说
This is the Los Angeles Police Department.
这里是洛杉矶警察局
Please vacate the premises immediately for your own safety.
为了你们的安全 请立刻撤离大楼 !
- Can we move it along? - Dr Katz's office.
- 大家怎么不动啊 ? -凯效医生办公室
- Hello. Dr Katz, please. - I'm sorry, he's not available.
- 你好，请接凯效大夫 - 对不起，他今天没空
For $300 an hour, you can put me through to his house in the Hamptons!
听着，我一小时付他 3 0 0 美元 所以马上给我接通他的家 !
This is the Los Angeles Police Department.
这里是洛杉矶警察局
Please vacate the premises immediately for your own safety.
为了你们自己的安全 请立刻撤离大楼
Mrs Whitmore!
总统夫人 !
You must leave now.
你们必须马上离开
The First Lady's secured. We're on the move.
第一夫人安全无苹，我们已经起飞
They're opening up!
他们开门了!
It's so pretty.
真漂亮
Get the hell outta here!
马上离开这里
Go ahead, pilot. We're ready to take off right now.
可以了，驾驶员 我们已经准备好马上起飞
Can we get a blanket for Patricia?
马上起飞，长官 给帕特丽落找一条丢子好吗 ?
Here.
给你
Time's up.
时间到了
Oh, crap.
噢，妈呀
Oh, my God! Come on, Dylan! We gotta go!
噢，我的天 ! 过来， 迪伦! 我们得走了 !
Come on, Boomer!
快点 : 布玛 !
Boomer!
布玛 ! !布玛 11!
Reports are unclear as to the extent of the devastation,
受损程度目前尚无详细报告
but it appears that Los Angeles, Washington, and New York are in ruins.
不过，据人们传说' 洛杉矶 华盛顿和纽约已变成一片废墟
Good God!
我的天哪 !
I've been sayin’ it.
我早就说过
I've been sayin’ it for ten damn years! Ain't I, Miguel?
我说了他妈的快十年了 我说什么来着，米盖尔 ?
Huh? I've been sayin’ it!
啊 ? 我星就说过
Dad, I don't feel good. Pull it over, man.
和爸爸，我病了 我觉得不舒服。请停一下
- We're gonna be all right, Troy. - Yeah, leave me alone. I got it.
-我们就快没事了，特罗伊 -别担心 呵， 不用管我
Miguel!
米盖尔 !
Look at all that.
你看看那儿
We could have evacuated the cities hours ago.
我们本可以提前数小时朴散市民
That's the advantage of being a fighter pilot.
这就是做战斗机驾驶员的好处
In the Gulf War, we knew what we had to do.
在海湾战争中 我们知道该做什么
This is just...
可是现在
«not simple any more.
没那么简单了
A lot of people died today.
今天死了很多人
How many didn't have to?
有多少人幸免呢 ?
Any news on my wife yet?
我妻子有消息了吗 ?
The helicopter never made it to Nellis.
直升机没有到内利斯
No radio contact.
失去联络了
Come on, Dylan. Stay close.
过来，迪伦。跟着我
Here it is.
这边走
What happened, Mommy?
这怎么了，妈国 ?
I don't know, baby.
我不知道，宝由
Our target is to the north,
目标在正北方
centred above what remains of downtown Los Angeles.
在洛杉矶市中心的废墟上空集结
Our Black Knight Squadron...
我们的“黑夜骑士”中队 作为攻击的先锋
- Are you scared, man? - Nope.
-你害怕吗 ? -不
- You?
-你呢? - 不由
- Hold me! - Hey, pay attention.
-抱抱我 -嘿'嘿' 注意点
Something you wanna add, Captain Hiller?
你有什么要补充的吗，希勒上尉 7
No, sir. Just a little anxious to whup ET's ass, that's all.
没有， 长官。只是恨不得 马上去踢外星人的屁股。就这些
You'll get your chance.
你会有机会的
You'll all get your chance.
你们都有机会
Good hunting. Dismissed!
好好打。解散
Let's kick the tyres and light the fires, Big Daddy!
好好收拾他们一顿吧， 伙计们 !
Ready to go, sir!
送他们回老家 !
Let's bring it home. Bring that bad boy home, Captain!
送这些坏蛋回老家
- You loose? - Yes, sir!
-上尉 ! 你紧张吗 ? -有点' 长官 !
- Got your victory dance? - Oh, I got it right here... yeah!
- 你准备好你的胜利雪茄了吗 ? -哦，时就准备好了 ! 耶!
Hey, don't get pre-patrol on me. We don't light up till the fat lady sings.
嘿， 嘿，别高兴得太量 ' 哥儿们 ! 不到最后的胜利我们可不轻易点着它
I'm all ears, brother!
我洗耳恭听， 老兄
You the man!
你当头儿 !
- All right, gentlemen, we're on. - General, it's NORAD.
-好吧，先生们 ' 我们开始 -将军， 北美防空司令部
- General Grey here. - Al?
-我是格雷 -了噢?
All communications with the cities are down.
与这些城市的卫星微波
- All systems gone. - For intelligence, we believe it's a total loss.
- 和地面联络全部中断 - 我想已经全部报销了
How about our boys? Where are they?
我们的飞行员呢 ? 他们在哪 ?
ETA to target, four minutes.
估计四分钠后到达目标
- [shouldn't have left her. - Don't worry about it, big man.
- 我不应该离开她 - 你不用担心， 大情人
I'm sure she got outta here before it happened.
我相信在出事前她已经离开了
Or, as the good Reverend would say:
或许就像牧师们说的那样
“Why we're on this particular mission, we'll never know."
“为何执行这项特殊的使命 我们永不知道”
“But I do know, here today,
“但是我知道，今天在这里
that the Black Knights will emerge victorious once again."
黑骑士将再次马到功成”
- Amen, man! - Amen, Reverend.
-阿门 -阿门:牧师
Holy God!
哦，天哪 !
Lock and load!
锁定目标 一切就绪
Roger that.
收到
LA attack squadron has Amraam missiles locked on target.
洛杉矶中队的阿菜姆 导弹已经锁定目标
Washington and New York squadrons report lock-on.
华盛顿和纽约中队也已锁定目标
- Fire at will.
-自由开火
Knights, we are red and free. Knight One, fox three!
其实们，看我们的了，骑士一号 发射三号弹 (中距离空对空导弹 )
Knight Three, fox three!
骑士三号，三号弹
Knight Seven, fox three.
其实七号，三号弹
The missiles have been fired.
导弹已经发身
- Are they not getting through? - No, not one.
-他们没有命中吗 ? -无一命中' 长官
Command, Knight One. Switchin' to Sidewinders, moving in.
呼叫， 骑士一号呼叫，骑士一号 迁回侧翼， 占据位置 僚机跟进 !
Knight Three, low 50 knots reference 120.
骑士三号，俯冲角5 0
Knight Seven, 120.
参照节数1 - 2 -0
Knight One, sweep lock. Fox two.
骑士一号，准备 发射二号弹 ! 〈红外导向空对空飞弹 )
Knight Seven...
骑士七号，二号弹
Come on!
来吧 ! 来吧 !
They must have a protective shield over the hull! Knights, pull up!
他们的外层一定有保护四 骑士们， 拉起来 ! 拉起来 !
- Knight Three, pull up! - Complete failure in the stators!
- 骑士三号，快拉升 ! -我的操纵杆不听使唤啦 !
Pull up!
拉起来 !
Blow through!
冲过去 ! 冲过去 !
Too many of 'em!
实在太多了 !
They got another one, sir.
我们又损失一架' 长官
Oh no, you did not shoot that green shit at me!
来呀 ! 你他妈的甫想打中我 !
I got ya covered, Big Daddy!
我来掩护你， 老大
Damn, they got shields, too!
他妈的，他们也有保护四 !
Let's go, Knights! Move, Knights! Move!
骑士们， 离开这里!撤撤 !
Jesus!
天哪 !
They got another one. And two more. They're dropping like flies.
又损失一架 ! 又有两架刚被击中 就像拍苍蝇一样
- We're losing it. - Get ‘em outta there.
- 就要全军覆没了 -好啦，叫他们撤出来
Squadron leaders, retreat to fallback position. Abort mission right away!
各中队队长， 撤离到退却位置 撤出战斗 ! 马上撤出战斗!
We'll have to make a run for this one! Let's get low and fast!
了听见了吗 ? 我们必须甩掩 这个家伙“，降低高度， 加速
I gotcha, Big Daddy! Let's get ‘em!
听明白了 ' 老大 ! 就这么办 ! 鸣哇
Watch the deck!
注意高度 !
- Squadron leader, abort! - This isn't happening fast enough!
-各中队队长，撤退 ! -你们的反应太慢了 !
Get 'em out!
让他们撤出来 !
- The monitor! Where's the picture? - We've lost the satellite.
-监视器 ! 图像不见了 ? -我们的卫星完了
- We got two on our six, Jimmy. Shackle! - Roger.
- 六点名方向有两架， 吉米 -明白!
Come on, come on! Move!
加油 ! 加油 ! 加油! 快!快1!快!
- You told me, like, quite all right! - They ain't got nothin’ for us! Let's push it!
- 你这么说就像没事一样，老大 “他们甫想占到便宜 ! 甩掉他们 !
- can't shake ‘em. - Yes, you can. Just the way I showed you.
- 我甩不掉 ! 我甩不掩 ! -你可以 ! 照我的办法做 !
- I'm gonna try somethin’. - Nothin’ stupid!
-我自有办法 ! -喂，千万别做傻事 !
- You know me! - That's what I mean.
-你了解我的 ! - 我说的就是这个 !
Jimmy, you can't bank at that speed!
吉米 ! 你在于什么 ? 那个速度不能转弯 !
Jimmy, he's closing on you!
吉米，敌机接近你了
- Put your mask back on! That's an order! - I can't breathe!
-把面具带上 ! 这是命令 ! - 我跨不上气了 !
Jimmy!
吉米 ! 吉米 !
No!
不11
Affirmative. We have incoming.
我们有客人了
- Let me have it, son. - You got it.
- 让我看看 -请看
Friendly?
善意的吗 ?
- Sergeant? - [don't think so.
-中士! -我想不是
Come on and get me!
来抓我呀 ! 来抓我呀 !
What are you shooting at?
你还想打谁 ?
Where you at, baby?! Come on!
你在那儿，宝页 ?来呀 ! 来呀 !
You can't hit nothin’!
你什么也打不着
See if you can fly that thing under cover!
看你被旱住了还能飞 ?
Hope you got an airbag!
希望你有安全气圳1也!
Son of a bitch!
狗娘养的
This way! This way!
我在这儿 ! 我在这儿 !
Get off! Get off of me!
别揪着我 ! 别揪着我 !
That's what you'll get! Look at you!
这就是你的下场 ! 哈哈 !
Ship all banged up! Who's the man?!
看看你自己 ! 飞船完蛋啦 ? 还能区了吗 ?
Huh? Who's the man?! Wait till l get another plane!
还想当老大吗 ? 等我再去搞一架飞机 !
I'm linin’ all your friends up, right beside you!
我要让你的朋友跟你躺在一起 !
Where you at? Huh? Where you at?
你在哪儿 ?咽 ? 你在哪儿 ?
Welcome to Earth.
欢迎来地球
That's what I call a close encounter.
这就是所谓的“第三类接触”
Baby, stay right here with Boomer.
宝贝， 就在这等着 和布玛一起等着
Keys. Come on, keys.
钥匙， 快点， 钥旺
Yes!
对呼 !
Come, baby. Come on!
快点 宝页， 加油，加油
Reports indicate that this battle has repeated itself all over the world
据报道，世界各地都有类似战斗
with the same results.
结果也基本相同
See, Troy? You're feelin’ better already.
嘿 ' 特罗伊 ? 感党好多了吧
Everyone's packin' up.
人人都在打包准备离开
- They said a spaceship is headed this way. - We'd better leave, too, then.
-他们说有一稻飞船朝这儿来了 -我们最好也走，你们说呢 ?
It's Air Force One, for crying out loud. Still he gets sick.
这可是大名易易的“空军一号” 可你还会晕机
- I don't feel too good. - Look at me, huh? Like a rock.
- 我感觉不太舒服 -看看我， 咽 ? 壮得像石头
Could be bad weather or good weather.
不管好天气坏天气都没关系
We could go up or down, back or forwards, side to side...
我可以上天上“，也可以下地 可以向后，又可以向前…
What did I say?
我说什么了 ?
- He still gets airsick, huh? - Yeah.
-他还是曙机 ' 喂 ? -是啊
Julius, with all of this...
朱利叶斯，发生了这么多事
I didn't get a chance to thank you two.
我，别…我还来不及 谢谢你们呢
All he could think of was getting to you.
他当时就想着来找你
There's still love there, I think.
我想他还是爱你的
- Love was never a problem. - All you need is love.
- 我们的问题不在这儿 - “你需要的是爱情”
John Lennon. Smart man. Shot in the back, very sad.
约翰 列依，人很精明 还是中枪死了，很郁阅
We've moved as many of our forces away from our bases as possible.
我们已经尽可能地 将部队撤离各基地
- But we've already sustained heavy losses. - I spoke with the Joint Chiefs at NORAD.
-不过我们仍遭到了严重损失 - 我和参谋长联席会议谈过了
They agree we must counterattack with a full nuclear strike.
他们同意我们发动一次 “饱和核打击”作为回击
Over American soil?
在美国的本土 ?
You're saying we should sacrifice more innocent American civilians?
你的意思是说我们应该 辆牲更多的无素美国公民吗 ?
If we don't strike soon, there may not be much of an America left!
如果我们不迅速反击，美国也 剩不下多少地方需要防御了
Sir! They've taken out NORAD.
长官' 他们已摧毁了防空司令部
- What? - It's gone, sir.
-什么? - 被摧毁了“长官
My God!
天哪
The Vice President? The Joint Chiefs?
副总统 ? 参谋长联席会议?
Mr President.
总统先生
We must launch.
我们必须行动了
A delay would be more costly than when you waited to evacuate the cities.
现在迟疑一刻的代价比你 延如居民朴散的还要大
You're not gonna launch nuclear weapons. You'll kill them and us. If we fire nukes...
你们不能使用核武器， 这样会让 外星人和我们同归于尽，若我们…
- Sir, may I remind you you are a guest here? - You ever hear of nuclear winter?
- 我提醒你' 你只是这儿的客人 - 你听说过核冬天吗 ?
- It's the end of life as we know it. - Just go.
-那是生命的末日 - 你走肥
I don't have to go. It can't be allowed!
我于嘛要走 ? 核武器不能用 !
- Shut up! Captain, get him out! - Don't tell him to shut up!
-闭嘴 ! 上尉， 把他给我带走 ! - 别对他说闭嘴 !
You'd all be dead if it wasn't for my David! None of you did anything to prevent this!
没有我的戴维，你们时都死了 你们想出什么办法对付他们了 ?
There was nothing we could do. We were totally unprepared for this.
我们无能为力 我们根本没有准备
- Don't give me that! - Come on.
- 别跟我说“没有准备” -好了 ， 朱利叶斯
It was, what? In the 1950s, you had that spaceship.
好像是一九五…一九五几年 你们就缴获了外星飞船
- Dad. Look... - Yeah, that thing you found in New Mexico!
-行了,和葵 -对 ' 你们在新墨西哥发现的
- Where was that? - Not the spaceship.
-在哪儿来着 ? -不，不是外星飞船
Roswell, New Mexico. You had the spaceship and the bodies!
罗效威尔， 新墨西哥 有飞船， 还有外星人忆体
They were locked up in a bunker.
它们都被锁在地下
Where was that?
在哪儿来着 ?
David! Area 51. Right?
戴维1 5 1区,对吗?
Area 51. You knew then! And you did nothing.
5 1区。你们都知道 可你们什么都没做
Sir.
先生
Regardless of what you may have read in the tabloids,
不管你在 小报上看到过什么
there have never been any spacecraft recovered by our government.
我们的政府从来没有 发现过飞船蛙毁
Take my word for it. There's no Area 51.
你要相信我。根本没有什么5 1 区
And there's no recovered spaceship.
也没有什么宇宙飞船
Excuse me, Mr President...
哦，对不起' 总统先生 ?
That's not entirely accurate.
这一点不太正确
What? Which part?
什么?哪一点?
Hold on, everybody. Hold on!
抓牢， 各位 ! 抓牢 !
- Can you give me a hand? - Sure.
- 你能搭把手吗 ? -没问题
Oh, God.
哦，上帝
OK, let's get this off.
好的， 好的。把这个搬开
Here, let me help you.
来，我来帮你
She's hurt pretty badly.
她伤得很重
But, nooo!
全完了 !
You got me out here, draggin’ your heavy ass through the burnin’ desert
你把我弄到这儿来，拖着你这个 大屁股，穿越这片该死的沙漠
with your dreadlocks stickin' out the back of my parachute.
还有你拖了一地的因子 你们来这儿可真会选时候
You gotta come down here with an attitude, actin’ all big and bad.
来了就大肆破坏
And what the hell is that smell?
你身上他妈的是什么怪味 ?
I coulda been at a barbecue!
我本来可以吃烤肉
But I ain't mad. It's all right, it's all right.
可我还没疯。没什么。这没什么
Do you need a lift, soldier?
要搭车吗，大兵 ?
When I flew overhead, I saw a base not too far from here.
我刚才在天上看见离这不远 有一个空军基地
It ain't on the map.
地图上没有
Trust me, it's there.
相信我，肯定有
Attention!
立正!
Mr President. General.
总统先生，将军
Welcome to Area 51. Please follow me.
欢迎到5 1 区来。请随我来
We're now 24 floors beneath the surface
我们现在在地下2 4层
and here's our main research facility.
这是我们的主研究机构
- Let's see it. - Sorry, sir, it's a clean room. It's static free...
- 进去看看 - 对不起，长官。这里是“无侍研究室”
Open the door.
把门打开
Yes, sir.
是:长官
My God.
上帝啊 !
Why the hell wasn't I told about this place?
为什么没人告诉我有这地方 ?
Two words, Mr President. Plausible deniability.
一言难尽' 总统先生 “似是而非的否认”
I don't get it. Where does all this come from?
我不明白。这是怎么建起来的 ?
How do you get funding for something like this?
这样的地方经费从何而来 ?
You don't actually think they spend $20,000 on a hammer,
买一把锤子用两万美元
$30,000 on a toilet seat, do you?
买一个马桶用三万美元 不就行了 ? 你说呢 ?
Mr President, this is Dr Okun.
总统先生，这是欧昆博士
He has headed up the research department on this project for the last 15 years.
1 5年来,他一直领导 这项研究工作
How do you do?
你好
Mr President!
总统先生
Wow!
哇
This...
呵
What a pleasure!
真是荣幸
As you can imagine, they...
您可以想象，他们…
They don't let us out much.
他们不让我们经常出去
I can understand that.
我可以理解
Well!
哦
I guess you'd like to see the big tamale, huh?
您肯定想看看那庞然大物 ' 虽 ?
Follow me.
随我来
She's a beauty, ain't she?
很美，不是吗 ?
As you can see from the repairs, we've been trying to put her back together since the '60s.
从修的痕迹可以看出 自从6 0年代 后期， 我们一直设法让它复原
You've had this for 40 years and you know nothing about 'em?
这家伙在这儿4 0年了 而你们对他们仍然一无所知 ?
Oh, hell, no. We know tons about ‘em.
哦，不，不 对他们“，我们知道得很多
But the neatest stuff...
不过，最奇妙的事是…
The neatest stuff has only happened in the last few days.
最奇妙的事是 最近几天才发生的
We can't duplicate their type of power so we've never been able to experiment.
看，我们无法复原它的发动机 因而一直无法试验
But since these guys started showing up, all the little gizmos inside turned on.
但是自从这些家伙出现以来 里边所有的小玩艺儿都动起来了
The last 24 hours have been really exciting!
过去的2 4小时真令人兴奋
Exciting? People are dying out there.
兴奋 ? 外面的人死伤惨重 !
Exciting isn't the word I'd choose to describe it!
我不会用“兴奋”来形容这件事
You're hoping to fly this thing, huh?
你们想让它再飞起来' 咽 ?
You said you can repair their technology. Can you tell us anything useful about them?
你说你了解他们的技术 能不能给我们讲点有用的东西 ?
Yeah. Well, I mean... They're not all that dissimilar from us.
哦可以，咽，听我说 外星人和我们并非完全不同
Breathes oxygen, comparable tolerances to heat, cold.
呼吸氧气、对冷热的耐受程度
Probably why they're interested in our planet.
也许因此他们才对地球感兴趣
You guys wanna see 'em?
你们想看看外星人吗 ?
This is...
哦，这是…
This is the vault.
这是停尸房
Or, as some of us have come to call it...
用我们这儿某些人的话说
the freak show.
“怪胎展览”
When we found ‘em,
发现他们时
they were wearing some sort of biomechanical suits.
他们穿着某种生物工程服装
Once we got ‘em off, we learned a great deal about their anatomy.
脱下外衣后， 我们了解了 他们详细的生理结构
Eyes, ears. No vocal chords.
有眼睛，耳采， 没有声带
We assume they communicate with each other by some other means.
我们认为他们用其它 更先进的方式彼此交流
You're obviously not thinking about hand signals and body language.
显然你说的不是手语 或者肢体语言吧 ?
It's some kind of extrasensory perception. Telepathy.
是某种超感官感知能力 心灵感应之类的
It's an organic life form.
他们是有机生命体
- Can they be killed? - Their bodies are just as frail as ours.
-可以被杀死吗 ? -他们的身体如同我们一样脆弱
These two died in the crash.
这两个坠地时就死了
This one a few weeks later.
哦，这个是数周后死的
You just have to get through their technology, which is,
你要领悟他们的技术
I'm sorry to say, far more advanced.
这个…请把我直言 简直高不可攀
David,
戴维
you unlocked part of their technology.
你领悟了他们的部分技术
- You cracked the code. - No, no. All l did was stumble on their...
- 你破解了密码 -噢， 不，不。我只是偶尔蒙对了
«Signal. I don't know how helpful I can be.
我不知道还能大多大忙
Why don't you show him what you've discovered so far?
你为什么不告诉他取得的发现 ?
Figure out what they haven't thought of yet.
说出他们还没想到的东西 ?
We'll see if you're as smart as we all hope you are.
让我们看看你是不是真的聪明
What code?
什么密码 ?
Captain Steven Hiller, US Marine Corps.
美国海军陆战了从上尉 史蓄文， 希勒
I'm sorry, Captain. You don't have clearance.
对不起，上尉。这里是军事禁区 没有出入证就不能过去
OK. Come here.
好吧，过来
You wanna see my clearance?
你想看我的出入证吗 ?
Get the hell out of the way!
你们把路内开 !
Oh, boy!
哦，宝页 !
- How long has he been unconscious? - About three hours.
-他失去知觉多久了 ? -大约3小时
Let's get him in containment.
送他进密闭箱' 恒温器 !
As the former head of the CIA, you knew about this place.
作为中央情报局的前任局长 你肯定知道这个地方
You should have told us about this when they first arrived!
他们刚到的时候，你就应当说出来
We wouldn't have launched a counterattack that cost the lives of hundreds of our pilots!
在发动反击前你就应当提醒我们 数百名美国飞行员就不会丧命 !
We could not have known that our fighters would've been that ineffective! Mr President.
我怎么知道我们的战斗机 对他们来说如此不堪一击
The little bit of information we have comes directly into this room.
这是我们直接获得的 仅有的一点信息
Atlanta, Chicago, and Philadelphia.
亚特兰大、芝加哥和费城
Destroyed.
全完了
NATO and Western Allied installations were the first to be taken out.
我们已获悉， 北约和 西欧联盟总部是最先被摧毁的
Then we were hit.
然后是我们
They knew exactly where and how to hit us.
他们很清楚 攻击哪里及如何攻击
- And our forces? - We're down to 15%.
-我们的部队剩下多少呢 ? -只剩下1 5%
If you calculate the time it takes to destroy a city and move on,
如果按照他们现有的 攻击和运动速度
we're looking at the worldwide destruction of every major city
3 6小时之后，全世界所有的
in the next 36 hours.
大城市将被全部摧毁
We're being exterminated.
我们要被斩尽杀绝了
Mr President!
总统先生 ?
This is Captain Steven Hiller.
这位是史蒂文，希勒上尉
- Captain. - Mr President.
-上尉 一 总统先生
Well done.
于得好
- Where is it now? - It's isolated in the containment lab, sir.
- 它现在在哪 ? -已经隔离在密闭实验室了，先生
I'd like to go see it.
我想去看一看
General, I'm really anxious to get back to El Toro.
将军' 呵 我想立刻回到埃尔托罗基地
Hasn't anyone told you?
没人告诉你吗 ?
El Toro has been completely destroyed.
埃尔托罗基地已经被完全摧毁了
We were lucky.
我们很幸运
Today was the first time I used the subway.
今天是我第一次乘地铁
Thank God for the Metro Rail.
感谢上帝让我这么做
These should last us a while.
这些够我们吃一阵子
Don't move. I'll get it for you. Stay still.
别动。我来帮你拿。别动
- He's your son? - He's my angel.
-是你儿子吗 ? - 是我的天使
Was his father stationed here?
他父亲在这儿服役 ?
Nah, he...
呵不
He wasn't his father.
他不是他答葡
But I was kinda hopin’ he wanted the job, though.
可我真希望他承担这个角色
- So what do you do for a living? - I'm a dancer.
-哦，那你靠什么为生 ? - 我是跳舞的
- Ballet. - No. Exotic.
-啊'芭蓄 -不' 艳舞
- Sorry. - Don't be. I'm not.
-噢，对不起 -不用抱歉。我不难受
It's good money. Besides my baby’s worth it.
收入很高 另外， 我的宝贝也要用钱
Dylan! Come here.
迪伦， 过来
I want you to meet the First Lady.
见见第一夫人
- Hello. - Hi.
-你好 -踢
I didn't know that you'd recognised me.
我没想到你会认出我
Well, I didn't want to say nothin’. I voted for the other guy.
我不想说什么 当时我没给你丈夫投票
Come on. Let's get this biomechanical suit off.
快点， 快点 我们剥开它的生物工程服装
Put the spreader right here, along the ridge.
把扩张器放在这儿 要沿着峭背
Microprobe thingamajig goes right here. Pick there. Good.
把微型探测器从这儿伸进去 夹住那儿。很好
All right, now spread it very, very gently.
好啦 ' 现在轻轻、轻轻地拉开
Let me get in.
我要切开了
Gentle, gentle, that's it.
轻点，轻点， 就这样
Run this right in...
把刀揪进去
All right.
没事了，好了
Let's proceed.
我们继续
Now comes the really icky part.
现在到了最恶心的部分
Oh, boy.
噢， 宝贝
This is one smelly, disgusting...
这是一个难闻的，恶心的…
Look at it.
攻' 看看它
It doesn't look alive, does it?
看上去好和象死了，是吗 ?
The arm is moving.
他的手名在动
Doctor? Doctor?
大夫?大夫?
Doctor?
大夫?
Don't move!
快把门打开。我打不开? ?
Dr Okun?
欧昆博士 ?
Release me.
放了我
- Open the door. Get him out! - No, wait.
-把门打开 ! 放他出来 ! -不，等等!
Release me.
放了我
I know there is much we can learn from each other
我想我们有许多方面可以互通
if we can negotiate a truce.
只要通过谈判达成停火
We can find a way to coexist.
我们可以找到一种共存的方式
Can there be a peace between us?
我们之间能实现和平吗 ?
Peace.
和平?
No peace.
没有和平
What is it you want us to do?
你们想要我们做什么 ?
Die!
死!
Mr President.
总统先生 ?
- Is that glass bulletproof? - No, sir.
-那块玻璃是防弹的吗 ? -不,长官
- Are you all right? - I saw his thoughts.
- 你没事有吧 ? - 我看见…他的思想
I saw what they're planning to do.
我看见了他们的计划
They're like locusts.
他们就象蝗虫一样
They're moving from planet to planet.
从一个行星到另一个行星
Their whole civilisation.
他们整体的文明
After they've consumed every natural resource, they move on.
他们的计划就是把所有的 自然资源消耗贻尽， 然后离开
And we're next.
地球就是下一个目标
Nuke 'em.
用核弹收拾他们
Let's nuke the bastards.
用核弹收拾这才杂种
Just my luck. No ice.
真是倒老。没冰块
I take it you've heard?
我想你听说了吧 ?
Hey, toast.
对，和干杯
- To the end of the world. - He didn't come to this decision lightly.
- 为世界末日于杯 - 他不是轻易作出这个决定的
He didn't have any other choice.
他已经别无选择
- Well, you still believe in him. - Well, he's a good man.
-是啊， 你依然信任他。哈 -呵，他是个好人
He'd better be. You left me for him.
哇 ! 他最好是，你离开我投奔他
Or, you know... for your career.
哦，为了' 为了你的事业
You know, it wasn't just my career.
不，这不仅是我的“事业”
It was the biggest opportunity of my life.
这是我一生最大的机会
I wanted my life to make a difference. I wanted my life to mean something.
我希望我的一生与众不同 我希望我的一生有意义
And... I wasn't... ambitious enough for you?
对，咽…对你来说 我的野心不够大 ?
David, you could have done anything you wanted. Research, development...
戴维，你本可以想做什么 就做什么。 研究，开发
I was happy where I was.
哦，宝贝' 我很满意我的工作
Haven't you ever wanted to be part of something special?
你就没想过要出人头地 ?
I was part of something special.
我已经与众不同了
Well, if it makes any difference, I never stopped loving you.
我一直都爱着你 这名你满意了吗 ?
But that wasn't enough, was it?
可是那还不够， 对吗 ?
Let's pick it up, man. Let's go!
快点装上去
Let's pick it up, man! We're on a tight schedule! Pick it up, man!
我们的时间很紧 这次任务很急，快点装 !
Pick it up!
把它抬起来， 伙计 !
What the hell are you doin'? Get outta there!
你在这儿于嘛 ? 马上滚出来 !
I got something I gotta handle. I'm borrowin'’ it.
我有要紧事要办，我只是借用一下
- No, you're not, sir. - Do you really wanna shoot me?
-不行， 长官 - 你真的想开枪吗 ?
Just tell 'em I hit you.
就说是我打了你
Command, this is Retal Op.
指挥部，我是“复仇”
Squadron is in the air. We are on station and awaiting instructions.
中队已经升空 我们已就位 ， 现在等候命令
Break formation. Head to targets.
明白。编队散开，飞向各目标
Sir.
长官
They're breaking formation.
这炸机编队散开
- We're initiating sequence code. - Verification: Alpha Zulu six eight niner.
-总统先生' 我们正启动发射密码 -确认: A、Z、6、8、9
Which city will be reached first?
最先到哪座城市 ?
Houston, Texas. ETA, six minutes and counting down.
德州的休斯顿 估计 6 分名到达， 倒计时
- Houston. - The major cities have been deserted.
- 休斯顿 - 主要城市已经疏散过了
Civilian casualties should be down to a minimum.
平民的伤亡应能降到最低
Command, this is Neighbourhood Watch. We are in position.
指挥部，我是“邻里守望者” 我们已经到位
Tracking monitors are locked on.
跟踪监视器已经锁定
We are going to visual recon.
我们将目视侦察
Roger.
明白
- We have confirmation. - Launch code confirmed.
-增强于扰图像过滤启动 -已经核实过了
Alpha Zulu six eight niner, standing by.
发射密码已核实 A、Z、6、8、9、准备
Laser targeting.
激光瞄准
Locked on.
锁定
We're locked on, sir. Do you wish to deploy?
目标已锁定， 长官。要发射吗 ?
Mr President, if you wish to deploy, the time is now.
总统先生，如果你要发射 现在正是时候
- Mr President? - Deploy.
-总统先生 ? - 发射
That's a go. Alpha Zulu six eight niner.
开始行动 A、Z、6、8、9。发射
Here we go.
现在发射
Bird's away.
“鸟已离梨”
We have visual confirmation of the missile. It's on target.
目视确认导弹已发射 正飞向目标
Approaching.
接近了
May our children forgive us.
但愿子孙们后代能原谅我们
Five seconds to impact. Three, two,
还有五秒钠。3、2
It's a hit!
噢,好啊 ! 打中了 !
Get down! Get down!
镇静 ! 镇静 !
Can we confirm that the target was destroyed?
能证实目标已被摧毁了吗 ?
Get the tank commander. Confirm the target was destroyed.
接通坦克指挥官 我需要确认目标已被摧毁
Red Arrow, Alpha 9723. Can you read?
红箭， 阿尔法、9、7、2、3 你们听见了吗 ?
- Repeat. You're breaking up. - We have lost visual.
- 重复，指挥官，你们断线了 -我们的仪器失灵了
Roger that. We're looking for confirmation.
明白。我们在等待确认 系统重新启动
We got the bastards.
那帮杂种完了
Good job, everyone! Congratulations.
太好了 ! 于得好, 各位。祝贺你们
Commander, do you have visual? We need visual confirmation.
指挥官，你能目视确认吗 ? 重复，我们需要目视确认
Has the target been destroyed?
目标被摧毁了吗 ?
Negative.
没有
Target remains.
目标依然存在
repeat, target remains.
重复， 目标依然存在
Call the other planes back.
命令其它飞机撤回
The others might have more luck. We shouldn't give up!
也许另一架刻炸机的运气好 我们不应该就这么放弃
I said call them back!
我说让他们回来
- Abort. - Abort mission.
-中止 -好的。任务中止
Issue the abort codes right away. This is an abort, full abort. Do you read?
马上发出中止代码 现在任务完全中止， 听见了吗 ?
Jasmine!
贾丝敏 ?
You're late!
你迟到了 !
You know I like to make an entrance.
你知道我喜欢给别人惊喜
- Where are we going? - Through there, sir.
-该往哪儿走 ? 一 总统先生
Mr President. Your wife is resting comfortably for the moment.
总统先生 苯夫人正在安静地休息
- Perhaps if we had gotten to her earlier... - Hey, there she is! Go on!
- 如果我们时一点治疗， 也许 -嘿 ! 她在那儿。去吧
- She doesn't look too good. - Your wife is bleeding internally.
-她看上去不大好 -苯夫人正在内出血，总统先生
- Perhaps if we'd gotten to her earlier... - What are you saying?
- 如果我们早点治疗 -嘿'，等一下。你想说什么 ?
We can't stop the bleeding.
我们无法为她赴血
If we'd...
如果我们…对她
There's nothing we can do for her.
我们已无能为力
We were worried. We didn't know where you were.
我们很担心 我们不知道你在哪儿
- You've gotten bigger, I think. - l did?
- 我觉得你长大了 -是吗 ?
You just keep growing and growing.
你不停地长啊长啊
I can't...
我不能
Hey.
嘿
Can you wait outside for a little bit so Mom can get a rest?
你在外边等一会，让妈妈休息一下?
Come on, Munchkin.
嘿， 过来，小家伙
I'm so sorry that I didn't come home when you asked me to.
很抱歉，你让我回家我却没有回
It's OK.
哦，没关系
The doctors...
大夫…说你就
think that you're... gonna be just fine.
就会好起来的
Liar.
骗人
Is Mommy sleeping now?
妈咪在睡觉吗 ?
Yeah.
是啊
Mommy's sleeping.
妈咪在睡觉。嘿
David!
戴维
- What the hell are you doing? - I'm makin’ a mess!
- 你在这儿于什么呢 ? -我正在捣乱 !
Yeah. This I can see.
对，看得出来
We gotta burn this toxic waste, pollute the air and rip up the ozone!
我们要燃烧这些有毒废物 污染空气，耗尽臭氧层
Cos maybe if we screw this planet up enough...
也许我们把地球毁得差不多了
«they won't want it any more.
外星人就不想要它了
Wait. David.
等等，等等
- Don't do this to yourself. Listen to me. - I'm listening.
-戴维，别自暴自弃，你在听吗 ? -我在听
Everyone loses faith at some point in their life. Even myself.
人这一生总有来失信心的时候 戴维。我也有过
I haven't spoken to God since your mother died.
你母亲死后 我就不和上帝说话了
You see, sometimes we have to remember what we still have.
是啊，有时候…必须记住 我们还拥有什么
Like what?
比如?
Well, you still have your health.
呵…你还拥有健康
David, you need your rest.
好了 ' 戴维， 你需要休息
Come on! Get off this freezing floor before you catch cold. Come on!
起来，别坐在冰冷的水泥地上 否则会感冒的。起来
- What did you just say? - About faith?
- 你刚才说什么 ? - 有关信念么 ?
- Well, you see, a man... - No.
-了呵，一个人的一生可以 -不,不,不
- The other part. - What? I don't want you to catch cold.
-不是这。另一部分 -什么 ?什么 ?我不想你感冒
What is that? What is the matter with you?
怎么了 ? 你到底怎么了 ?
- Genius. - Genius?
- 你是天才 -天才?
My dad. A total genius.
老侈，地道的天才
Jerry, wake up.
杰瑞 ? 醒柄
We got work to do. Get everybody down here right away.
我们有事做了 让这儿所有的人马上来
- Look at that! - Wow!
-看那家伙 ! -哇!
- Does that thing really fly in outer space? - It most certainly does.
- 那家伙真的在外太空飞过吗 ? - 应该是吧
- Sure doesn't look like it. - They're here.
- 看起来可不像 -他们来了
- All right, what's this all about? - [have no idea.
-喂'康妮' 这是怎么回事 ? - 我不知道
Get everybody off. Right, clear the platform. Let's go.
叫所有人都下去。好的 诸位， 离开平台， 我们走
- Major Mitchell. Do you have a pistol? - What?
“-米切尔少校 ， 你有手枪吗 ? -什么?
- Have you got a gun? - Sergeant, your sidearm.
-你有检吗 ? -中士，你的枪
See that Coke can on top of the alien craft? Think you can shoot that thing off?
看那儿，外星飞船上的可乐缸 你能把它打下来吗 ?
- Shoot it. - Sir?
- 打吧，试试看 -长官?
Go ahead.
打吧
- What the hell are you doing? - I'm sorry. My fault.
- 你到底想于什么 ? - 对不起，都怪我，都怪我
That Coke can was protected by the craft's shield.
那个可乐负受到 飞船保护罩的保护
- We can't penetrate it. - What's your point?
- 因此无法突破他们的防御 -我们已经知道了。你想说什么 ?
My point is, if we can't beat their defences, then we gotta get around them.
如果我们不能突破他们的防御 那我们就必须和兜圈子
Major. One more time... Any time.
少校， 再来一次。来吧
- How did you do that? - I gave it a cold.
- 你是怎么做的 ? -我让它 “感冒”
I gave it a virus. A computer virus.
给它输入病毒，电脑病毒
Are you telling us you can send out a signal that will disable all their shields?
你是说你能发射一个信号 使他们的所有保护四失效 ?
Just like they used our satellites against us, we can use their own signal against them.
他们用我们的卫星对付我们 我们也能用他们的信号对付他们
If we plant a virus into that mother ship,
如果我们在他们的 母舰里植入病毒
it's gonna filter down into all the corresponding ships below.
所有与之关联的飞船都会被感染
I'm sorry. I don't understand. How exactly do we infect the mother ship with this virus?
对不起，我不明白 我们怎么才能使母舰染上这种病毒 ?
We're... We're gonna
哦，我们可以
have to... fly their alien craft out of our atmosphere and dock with it.
必须，阿…把外星人的飞船 开出大气层，与之对接
We can enter here, as shown in these satellite photos.
我们可以从这儿进去 正如卫星照片所示
We then upload the virus, set off some kind of explosion which'll disable it.
然后我们上传病毒，然后在那里 制造某种爆炸，使之完全竣痪
That'll disorient the smaller ships below and that could buy you some time to...
这样小的飞船就会失去指挥 这样我们至少可以赢得一些时间
to take ‘em... take 'em out. Take ‘em down.
了呵，把他们…消灭掩，击落
Do your... Do your stuff.
杀个…杀个痛快
- This is ridiculous! - How long would their shields be down?
-这太可笑了 “他们的保护四会失效多久 ?
Eh... l dunno. A matter of minutes.
呵，我不知道。也许几分钟的事
You want us to coordinate a counterstrike with a window of a few minutes?
你是要我们在这几分钟之内 组织一场全世界的大反攻 ?
- With shields down, it might be possible. - Oh, please!
- 如果没有保护四，也许可以 -噢' 拜托
We don't have the manpower or the resources to launch that kind of a campaign!
我们没有足够的人力和资源 发动这种规模的战役
Not to mention that this whole cockamamie plan
更何况这一整套荒廖可笑的计划
depends on a machine that no one in this world is qualified to operate.
全依赖于一部世界上 没人会开的机器
1 wouldn't say that, sir.
我想不是的，长官
I've seen them in action. I'm aware of their manoeuvring capabilities.
我见过这种飞船的动作 非常熟悉它的各项操作性能
With your permission, General, I'd like the opportunity to try.
将军， 如果你允许， 我想试试看
That thing is a wreck.
这东西是堆废铁 !
It crash-landed in the ‘50s. We don't even know if it's capable of flying!
它是五十年代人坠毁的 ! 我们甚至不知道它是否还能飞
Jim, remove the clamps.
吉姆，放下支架
Any questions?
还有问题吗 ?
Let's do it.
咱们试试
All right, you heard the President...
好了 。总统已经下令…
- Good luck, pilot. - Thank you, Mr President.
-祝你好运， 战士 -谢谢， 总统先生
A virus.
病毒
Your idea.
你的主意
That's right.
说的没错
Do you really think you can fly that thing?
你真的认为你能开吗 ?
Do you really think you can do all that bullshit you just said?
你真的认为你那些 白旦梦都能实现吗 ?
I understand you are upset over your wife's death.
我知道。夫人死了， 您心里很乱
But that's no excuse for making another fatal mistake.
但这不能是犯下 另一个大错的借口
No, my mistake was to appoint a snivelling weasel like you as Secretary of Defense.
不。我犯过的唯一错误是任命像你 这样 胆小如鼠的人当我的国防部长
- You don't understand! - However,
- 我想您还不太明白 -不过
that is one mistake I am thankful to say that I don't have to live with.
我很庆幸有一个错误 我不需要再犯下去了
- Mr President... - Mr Nimsiki,
一 总统先生 - 尼姆斯基先生
you're fired.
你被撤职了
Let's organise every plane we can find and get us some goddamn pilots to fly ‘em.
把能找到的飞机都集中起来 再去找些飞行员驾驶它们
- Yes, sir. - He can't do that.
-是:长官 - 他不能这么做
Well, he just did.
呵，他刚刚 ' 做了
Command has attempted to list casualties and losses, but information is sketchy.
司令部想做出一份伤亡及损失清单 但我们只有一些大概的数据
We know they've lost the Belgian contingent in the Sinai.
现在我们知道比利时 分队在西奈被歼
There's a strong possibility reinforcements are hiding in the Golan Straits.
不过有一些增援部队 很可能隐蔽8在黄金海峡
- What is he saying? - They're getting a signal. Old Morse code.
-他在说些什么 ? “他们收到一个老式摩尔斯电码
It's from the Americans.
是美国人发的
They want to organise a counteroffensive!
他们想组织一次反攻
It's about bloody time! What do they plan to do?
现在是时候了“， 他们打算怎么办 ?
We have confirmed reports of combat-ready divisions
我们已经核实，做好战斗准备
- in Europe, the Middle East, and Asia. - Impressive. Considering it's all done with...
-欧洲、中东和亚洲各地 -太好了。想想这一切靠的都是
Morse code.
摩尔斯电码
- The armed forces here? - We have sufficient aircraft, but...
- 部队集结完毕了吗 ? -我们的飞机数量足够作战，不过
- But what? - Pilots are comin’ up short.
-不过什么 ? - 飞行员出现短缺
Well, then, find ‘em.
是吗 ? 去找吧
Ham radio operators from New York to Japan trade rumours of military forces in hiding,
从纽约到日本的业余 无线电爱好者散布训言称
unwilling to reveal themselves for fear of annihilation...
军队因为害怕被 歼灭正在四处躲藏
We're planning to launch a counteroffensive.
目前我们正计划发动 一次大规模反击
With our depleted manpower,
但是，由于人员大量消耗
we're asking that anyone with flight experience come forward.
因此任何有飞行 经验的人请站出来
Military training is preferable, but anyone who can fly would be useful.
最好受过军事训练 不过， 会开飞机的都有用武之地
I can fly. I'm a pilot.
我会开。我是飞行员
All right, guys! Listen up!
好啦诸位，注意听 !
Pay attention. These F-18s are very different than the jets you piloted.
请大家注意， 这些F - 1 8与你们 以前驾驶的喷气机有很大差别
- It's strong. - Forgive the expression,
-这酒劲儿很大 -实话跟大家说
but this is a crash course in modern avionics.
你们将恶补现代， 航空电子学知识
- Keep it comin’. - OK, you got it!
- 再去弄点，再去弄点 -好吧，听你的
All right, listen up. First we need some background information on your experience.
好的，听着。在开始之前要先了解 一下诸位的飞行经验到底如何
Let's start with you.
就从你开始
Who, me?
谁?我?
Well, I'm Russell Casse, sir.
我:我叫，阿 卢塞尔: 凯西，长官
And after 'Nam I got into crop-dusting.
呵' 我 呵， 越战归来后 呵，当撤药飞行员
And been doing that ever since.
呵，一直于到现在
On a personal note, sir, I'd just like to add that
我得提一下，长官 我得补充一点
ever since I was kidnapped by aliens 10 years ago,
十年前我曾被外星人绑架
I have been dyin’ for some payback.
我一直想报仇
I just want you to know that I won't let you down.
我想让你知道 我不会让你失望的
You have one tactical nuclear missile
我们在右贾下加装了发射器
we're loading into this launcher under the right wing.
挂载了一枚战术核导弹
This is the firing mechanism.
这是发射机构
It'll be attached to the ship's main console.
将被连接在飞船主控制板上
Just like the Amraam launch pad on a Stealth.
和隐形飞机上的发射台差不多
Except the nuke will not detonate at impact.
只是核弹受到撞击也不爆炸
You'll have 30 seconds to get your asses out of there.
你们将有 3 0 秒钟的时间 从那儿撤离
Good luck, gentlemen.
祝你们好运，先生们
30 seconds.
3 0秒
It's the strongest radio transmitter we had. It'll tell us when you've uploaded the virus.
这是现有最强的无线电发射机 病毒传输完毕后，它将通知我们
30 seconds. Don't you think that's cutting it too close?
3 0秒 ?难道你不觉得 这段时间太短了 ?
We're gonna be well on our way back home before we shoot that thing off.
哦，在于掉他们之前 我们早就在返航的路上了
Why you? David!
为什么是你 ? 戴维 ?
I don't understand why you can't show someone else how to plant the virus.
我不明白你为什么不教别人如何 如何植入病毒
No. Something may go wrong.
不， 不。也许会出现差错
I may have to think quickly, adjust the signal.
我必须保持思维敏捷 呵，调整信号
Who knows? Hey, you know how I'm always trying to save the planet?
管他呢，你知道我很喜欢 拯救这颗行星
Here's my chance.
这是我的机会
Now he gets ambitious.
你终于雄心勃勃了
OK. All right, l guess that's good enough.
好了。好了“。我想还算不错
So. How do I look?
我看上去怎么样 ?
Oh, thank you. You're a lot of help.
哦，谢谢。你帮了我大忙
- You're late! - Well, you know me.
-你迟到了 -你了解我的
I know. You like to make a big entrance.
我了解。你喜欢给人惊喜
Listen. Before we do this, I just wanna say I'm sorry.
呵， 听着 。在开始之前 我只想说声对不起
Sorry for what, babe?
为什么对不起， 宝贝 ?
I should have done this a long time ago.
我很久以前就该娶你了
- Do you have the ring? - Yes, sir.
- 你有戒指吗 ? -啊, 有
Here, make yourself useful.
给。看你的了
Witnesses?
见证人呢 ?
- We got hung up. - Well, let's get this show on the road.
- 对不起，我们来晚了 -好， 现在我们开始吧
Dearly beloved, we're gathered here in the sight of God
亲爱的兄弟姐妹们 我们聚集在这里
and in the presence of these witnesses
在上帝和这几位见证人的注视下
to join this man and this woman in holy matrimony.
参加这位男士和 这位女士的幸福婚礼
Any person who can show good cause why these two should not wed,
任何人如果有任何正当的 理由证明他们不可结婚
please speak now or for ever hold your peace.
请现在就说出来 否则请永远保持沉默
Steve, will you take this woman to be your wedded wife,
史蒂夫，你愿意娶这位女士 为你的合法妻子
to live together with her in the holy state of matrimony?
与她共同生活 一起享受婚姻的幸福吗 ?
Will you love her, comfort her, honour and keep her in sickness and in health,
你愿意爱她、抚慰她并忠于她 无论她健康还是患病 ?
and, forsaking all others,
你愿意舍弃其他人的诱惑
keep yourself only for her as long as you both shall live?
在有生之年只忠于她一人吗 ?
1 will.
我愿意。嘱 !
Good morning.
早上好
They're a little young.
他们有点年轻
That they are.
确实如此
They look a little nervous.
他们好像有点紧张
I need all flight crews to report to their designated areas.
所有飞行员立刻到 各自的指定区城报告
- Major. Can I borrow that? - Sir.
-少校，借我用一下 -长官
Good morning.
早上好
In less than an hour,
再过一小时
aircraft from here will join others from around the world.
这里的战机将与 世界各地的盟友并肩战斗
And you will be launching the largest aerial battle in the history of mankind.
你们将参与人类历史上 最大的空战
Mankind. That word should have new meaning for all of us today.
人类。这个词今天对于我们 所有人将赋予新的意义
We can't be consumed by our petty differences any more.
我们不能再为 小小的分歧而自相残杀
We will be united in our common interest.
我们将为共同利益团结起来
Perhaps it's fate that today is the Fourth of July.
也许天意如此 今天正好是是独立纪念日
And you will once again be fighting for our freedom.
你们将再一次为自由而战
Not from tyranny, oppression or persecution.
不是为了反抗暴政、压迫和迫害
But from annihilation.
而是免遭毁灭
We're fighting for our right to live.
是为生存的权力…
To exist.
而战斗
And should we win the day,
如果我们今天能够胜利
the Fourth of July will no longer be known as an American holiday,
七月四日将不仅是 美国人民的假日
but as the day when the world declared in one voice,
而且将使全世界人民 发出同样的呐喊
“We will not go quietly into the night!"
“我们不会黑黑地在黑暗中沉沦 1 ”
“We will not vanish without a fight!"
“我们不会就这样坐以待丝1”
“We're going to live on!"
“我们要活下去 !”
“We're going to survive!"
“我们一定要生存下来 ! ”
Today, we celebrate our Independence Day!
今天 我们要庆祝我们的独-立-日!
- Let's go! - Mr President. Right this way, sir.
-出发! -总统先生， 请这边走
- I've got your gear over here. - Good luck!
-您的装备都在这儿 -祝你好运
I've got you a jumpsuit and your gear is here. You've got your choice of helmets.
我为您准备了伞兵服，其它装备 都在袋子里，您选个头盔吧
Mr President, I'd sure like to know what you're doing.
总统先生 我希望您知道您在于什么 ?
I'm acombat pilot, Will.
我是战斗飞行员
I belong in the air.
我属于这片天空
OK, sir. Let's get you airborne.
好了 长官， 您的飞机就在那边
As soon as I get back, we're gonna light those fireworks, right?
喂，等我一回来 我们就去放焰火， 好吗 ?
Here. Take these.
给，拿着
Just in case.
以防万一
Where's...
给…
I'm very proud of you.
我为你感到骄傲
Be careful, OK?
要小心， 好吗 ?
It's time.
是时候了
- Il love you.
-我爱你
Oh, damn! Wait a minute.
噢， 糟糕 ! 等一下' 等一下，等等
- We gotta find some cigars. I can't... - Here!
-我没带雪匣。我不能…不带 -给1给!
Take these. My last two.
拿去吧。最后两支
You are a lifesaver.
你救了我的命
Almost put a hex on the whole damn thing!
今天差点就走了走运
- Missile launch. - Oh, crap!
- 导弹发射 -噢，妈的
What do I hit? Which one?
我磁哪儿 了 ? 哪一个 ?
I picked a hell of a day to quit drinkin’.
我不该今天才戒酒啊
This is our victory dance.
这是庆功用的
Not until the fat lady sings.
不到最后一刻，不能抽
Oh. Yes, OK.
噢,好,好的
- This is important. - Fat lady. I gotcha.
-这很重要 -噢，“胖女人”。我懂了
Open launch tunnel.
打开发射通道
Shaky, huh? Is it gonna do this the whole way?
有点晃，咽? 一路上都会这样吗 ?
Make sure your seat backs are in their upright position.
请保持靠背坚直 并将折芭餐盘收起扣好
Yeah. Is it?
啊，对吗 ?
Let's rock'n'roll.
开始摇滚吧
Oops.
哄哟 !
Oops? What does that mean?
“隘哟 ? ”这是什么意思 ?
No, I got it. Some jerk didn't put the thing...
哦，我明白了 瞧，有人把它贴反了
What do you mean, saying "oops" there?
我是问为什么“隘哟” ?
What do you say we try that one again, huh?
我们再试一次你看怎么样 ?
Yes, without the "oops".
行，行，只要别说“哎哟”就行
Thataway!
朝那边飞
I have got to get me one of these!
有钱我也要买一架自己飞着玩 !
- What was that? Don't do that! - Just tryin’ to get a feel for the old girl.
-你在于什么 ? 别这样飞 ! -我只是想熟悉一下性能，就这些
- Look, no hands! - Steve!
-瞧，松手了1! -史蔓文1 1
- You're all secure, sir. - Grey, do you read me?
-一切正常， 长官 -格雷，能听见吗 ?
Roger, Eagle One. Your primary target has shifted course.
收到，飞应一号 你的目标已改变航向
- Which way they headed? - [ think our secret's out.
-他们在朝哪儿飞? - 我们的秘密被发现了
They're headed straight for us.
他们直接朝我们飞来
ETA, 26 minutes.
估计2 6 分钠后到
- You still with me over there? - What the hell was I thinking?
-你还活着吗 ? -我究竟在干什么 ?
I've been waiting for this my whole life.
我一生都在等待这一时刻
Head straight for it.
一直往前飞
- What the hell? - Don't touch ‘em. Don't!
-怎么回事 ? - 别动他们 ， 别动，别动
I was counting on this. They are bringing us in.
不出我所料 他们正在引导我们
- When the hell was you gonna tell me? - Oops.
- 你为什么不时点告诉我 ? -哄哟
We've got to work on our communication.
我们必须保持良好沟通
- We have visual. - Do not engage until we've confirmed
-已看见目标 - 在确认货物已经
- the package has been delivered. - Roger.
- 发出之前不要行动 -明和白
Major, what happens if that thing gets here
少校 ， 如果在病毒植入之前
before the virus is planted?
那家伙就到了怎么办 ?
This facility's buried deep within a mountain.
这座建筑深深地埋在山里
- It should provide us some protection. - Great.
-能提供足够的保护 -很好
What about the people outside?
外边的人怎么办?
Lieutenant Sell? We got incoming.
上校， 我们有一些客人
Oh, my God.
贡 ' 天哪
Look at that.
你看那儿
There must be thousands of ‘em. Millions. What the hell are they doing?
他们的数量数以千计 是数以百万。他们到底在于嘛 ?
Looks like they're preparing an invasion.
好像在准备发动侵略
Hey, I don't like this! This is stupid. They can see us.
我不喜欢这样 这，这很思春。他们能看见我们
No. This thing comes fully loaded.
不:不,不*这东西装备齐全
AMIFM radio, reclining bucket seats and
调频收音机， 可以放平的座椅
power windows.
还有电动车窗
Come on, baby.
快点: 宝贝! 快点， 宝贝
We're in.
接通了 ! 哦， 好的
Do it.
上传病毒
Sir, he’s uploading the virus.
长官， 他们在上传病毒
Eagle One, the package is being delivered.
飞座一号 ， 货物正在发出
Stand by to engage.
准备开始行动
Roger. Eagle One, check left.
明白。飞认一号，转向左翼
Listen up! We have an emergency situation.
大家注意 ! 现在情况紧急
We need you to grab everything you can.
我们要求所有人 立刻带上自己的东西
Only what you can carry. We need to get you inside immediately.
只拿那些随身的物品 马上跟我们进来
The virus is in.
病毒已经输入
All we can do now is pray.
我们现在所能做的就是祈祷
- Delivery complete. Engage. - Delivery complete. It's a go!
- 货已发出。行动 - 货已发出。开始行动
Eagle One. Fox three.
飞座一号' 三号弹
Gentlemen, this is it.
先生们， 是时候了
Come on, come on.
快， 快，快
Virus ineffective. Disengage.
病毒无效。停止行动
- Get your people out. - Disengage.
-叫你的人撤回来 - 停止行动
Rear flank, follow suit.
撤退， 保持队形
Hold on, Command.
等等，指挥官
- [ want another shot at it. - Sir, strongly recommend you disengage.
- 我想再试一次 - 长官，我强烈建议您撤出战斗
Eagle One. Fox three.
飞座一号' 三号弹
- Direct hit! - It's a hit! Squadron leaders, fire at will!
- 直接命中 ! -命中 ! 各中队队长， 自由开火 !
We're going in. Squadron leaders, take flight.
跟我来。各中队长，进入作战位置
- Eagle Six at seven. - Eagle Five at three.
- 飞褒六号 ' 七点钟方向 - 飞唐五号 ， 三点钟方向
Eagle One. Fox two.
飞座一号 ' 二号弹
Eagle Twenty! Fox two!
飞褒二十号，二号弹
Evasive manoeuvres! Squadron leaders, evasive manoeuvres!
注意规避 ! 各中队长， 注意规避 !
Prepare to engage!
准备近距离格斗 !
All right, Mr President! Here we go!
好啊， 总统先生， 我们来了 !
All right, baby. I've gotcha!
好咬，宝页 ' 跑不了了咬 !
Payback's a bitch, ain't it?
君子报仇，十年不晚
OK. Job's done. Let's go home.
好了“， 任务完成，我们回家吧
Gladly.
遵命
- What's up? - It's stuck.
-怎么了 ? -卡住了
- What? - It's not responding. It's stuck.
-什么? - 它没有反应。卡住了
Try it again.
再来一次
Come on!
跟上1!跟上1!
Come on! Inside!
快点 !快点 ! 进来!
- Go to the elevator! - Hurry!
-上电梯 ! -快点!跟上!I快!快!跟上!
Steve!
史蔓文 ! 史莫文 !
- What are you doin’? - They're overriding the system.
-嘿' 你他妈的于什么? -不是我于的，他们正在接管系统
Oh, shit!
噢，妈的!
Hide.
呵' 快躲!
Everybody hold someone's hand. Hold hands.
大家拉起手来。拉起手
Come on in.
你过来
Eagle Seven, fox two.
飞座七号' 二号弹
Eagle Three, fox two.
飞座三号 ， 二号弹
We're running out of missiles, sir. We're not causing enough damage.
我们的导弹用光了“， 长官 没有造成足够破坏
It's directly over us.
它悬停在我们上空
They're preparing to fire their primary weapon!
他们正准备发射他们的主炮 !
Then let's take it out before it takes us out.
那我们就必须先发制人 !
Target at 12 o'clock!
目标，1 2 点钟方向
My God! They're everywhere!
上帝呀，满天都是!
- Bandits on our tail! Locked on! - l see 'em.
- 你被敌机咬住了，它们在瞄准! -我看见了 ! 我看见了 !
Squadron leaders, I want a weapons check!
各中队长，检查武器存量
You're outta time! Disable it now!
已经没时间了 你们必须马上氛毁它 !
I'm in range. Locking on.
我在射程之内 ! 锁定
I've got tone. Eagle One, fox two!
我被咬住了 飞座一号， 二号弹 !
That is a negative impact.
攻击没有成功!
I'm out of missiles. Eagle Two!
我没有导弹了“。飞座二号 !
I'm on it.
我来了 !
Jesus!
珊 :天哪 !
- All missiles have been fired. - Outta time! Get your ass outta there!
- 长官， 导弹全部射完 ! -已经没时间了 ! 马上全都撤回来 !
- We're not done yet! - Get as far away as you can!
-任务还没完成不能走 ! - 你们撤得越远越好 !
Doesn't anyone have any missiles left?
谁还有导弹 ?
Sorry I'm late, Mr President!
对不起我来晚了， 总统先生 !
I got hung up back there!
我受到了一点阻挡
- Pilot, you armed? - Armed and ready, sir!
-你有导弹吗 ? - 箭在弦上长官
I'm packin'!
我弹药充足
- Who is that guy? - Put him on speaker.
-那人是谁 ? -接通他的飞机
- Pilot, identify yourself. - It's me!
- 驾驶员，报上姓名 -是我
Russell Casse, sir.
卢塞尔 : 凯西
I told you I wouldn't let you down!
我说过不会让你失望的
Just keep those guys off me for a few more seconds, will ya?
让他们再掩护我几秒钟好吗 ?
OK. Echo Niner, Echo Seven, take flanking positions. Look after this guy, OK?
可以。呼叫九号，呼叫七号 占领侧翼位置，你们来关照他
All right, boys. Let's give Mr Casse some cover!
明白， 弟兄们 ! 捷护凯西先生
Gentlemen! Let's plough the road!
先生们， 我们给他开路 !
We'll draw them off and it's all yours!
我们把他们赶走， 全看你的了 !
Look out! Comin’ through!
险! 小心 1我来了 !
I've got tone.
我已经锁定
Eagle Twenty. Fox two.
飞褒二十号，二号弹
It's jammed.
卡住了!
it won't fire.
不能发射 !
Dammit!
妈的!
Do me a favour.
请帮个忙
Tell my children I love them very much.
告诉我的孩子， 我非常爱他们
All right, you alien assholes!
好吧，外星臭小子们 !
In the words of my generation,
用我们这一代的话说
up yours!
抄家伙吧 !
Dad! What's he doing?
和葡? ! 他在于什么 ?
Come on, baby!
来呀，宝页 !
Come on, baby, come on!
来呀，宝页 ! 来呀!
Good luck, buddy.
祝你好运， 伙计
Hello, boys! I'm back!
好啊，宝页 ! 我回来了1 !
He did it! The son of a bitch did it!
他成功了 ! 那家伙他成功了 !
All right!
太好了 !
What your father did was very brave.
你的爸爸是一位勇士
You should be proud of him.
你应该为他骄傲
lam.
没错
We know how to take 'em out, General. Spread the word.
我们知道如何消灭他们了 将军。把消息传出去
Get on the wire to every squadron around the world.
立刻把这个消息通知 世界各地的盟友
Tell them how to bring those sons of bitches down.
告诉他们如何消灭那些混蛋
What do you think?
你怎么看 ?
Checkmate.
将军
Well, it's funny. I always thought things like these would kill me.
哦，真有趣 我总以为抽雪茄会要了我的命
It's been a pleasure.
很高兴和你合作
Steve, you too.
史蒂文，彼此彼此
Only one thing left to do.
只有一件事还没做
- Ready? - Yes, sir.
-准备好了 ? -是:长官
Hey, all right! Look at us.
嘿 !你好 ? 看看我们 !
Take a look at the earthlings. Goodbye!
好好看看地球人，再见
- Y'all take care. Nothing but love for ya! - Goodbye!
- 你们多保重。我真舍不得你们 -再见
Do you think they know what's about to happen?
你认为他们知道 将要发生什么事吗 ?
Not a chance in hell. Good night!
他们知道个屁。了晚安
Peace!
和平万岁 !
We're loose. Can you get us outta here in 30 seconds?
松开了。 3 0 秒内我们能出去吗 ?
- l ain't heard no fat lady! - Forget the fat lady. Drive us outta here!
-这事还没完丙 ! -快别嚼味啦 ! 马上离开这儿 !
- They're chasing us. - You think?
-他们在追我们 ! -哦，是吗' 真的?
- Oh, that was a hit. - We're not hit! Stop side-seat driving!
-哦 !哦'被打中了。被打中了 -没中 ! 没中 ! 别指手画脚 !
Left! Tunnel! Exit left!
向左 ! 向左 ! 隧道 ! 隧道 ! 出口， 出口在左边 !
- Where the hell do you think I'm goin’? - OK. We're...
- 你以为我会去哪儿 ? -好的,好的
- They're closing up on us. - Shut up!
- 啊也， 我们要被关起来了 ! -闭嘴，闭嘴，闭嘴 !
Go faster, must go faster. Go, go, go!
开快点， 必须快点，必须快点
Elvis has left the building!
哇喔 ! ! 我早就知道肯定没事 !
Thank you very much.
哦，非常感谢
I love you, man.
哦，哦，我爱你
They're goin’ down all over the world, Tom. We got ‘em beat.
他们正在被陆续捧毁， 汤姆 我们大获全胜
How about our two delivery boys? Any word from them?
送货的小子们怎么样了 ? 有消息吗 ?
We lost contact with Captain Hiller and Levinson nearly 20 minutes ago.
我们与希勒上尉和莱文森 大约2 0分名前失去联系
Hold it!
等等
Hold on, sir. I've got something on radar.
等等，长官 ! 雷达有所发现 !
Sorry, sir.
对不起，长官
- Good job. - Thank you.
-二得好
- Well done, Captain. - Yes, sir. Thank you, sir.
-于得好，上尉 -谢谢，长官
David...
戴维
Not bad.
于得好
Thank you, Mr President.
谢谢，总统先生
Not too bad at all.
真得很不错
Oh, so this is healthy?
哦，这算健康吗 ?
Oh, I could get used to it.
哦，我会习惯的
Happy Fourth of July, Daddy.
祝您独立日快乐, 欧地
Same to you, Munchkin.
也祝你快乐' 小仙文
Didn't I promise you fireworks?
我不是答应你会放焰火吗 ?
Yeah.
对
Subtitles by Visiontext
谢谢观赏 !